Welcome back, everyone.
欢迎回来，各位。
Next we have session two on ICN for
接下来我们将进入第二场关于ICN的会议。
wireless edge networking chaired by Eve Schooler from Intel.
无线边缘网络会议，由英特尔的Eve Schooler主持。
Eve, go ahead.
Eve，请开始。
>> Well, we've got three great presentations today.
我们今天有三场精彩的演讲。
We're gonna lead off with one on the topic of ICN when a program overview,
我们将首先介绍一个关于ICN的主题，提供一个程序概览。
by Dr. Shree Katyayani Tsikata Suara, otherwise known as Katyayani.
由Shree Katyayani Tsikata Suara博士主持，她也被称为Katyayani。
Who's a senior research scientist at Intel labs,
谁是英特尔实验室的高级研究科学家，
leading research in information centric networks for edge computing.
领先的研究在面向边缘计算的信息中心网络。
And her research focuses on applications where ICN can add value to industry.
她的研究重点是ICN能为行业增加价值的应用领域。
Katyayani is the Intel PI for the joint Intel-NSF ICN-WEN Center.
Katyayani是英特尔与美国国家科学基金会联合成立的ICN-WEN中心的英特尔首席研究员。
Take it away Katyayani >> Thank you so much Eve,
太感谢你了，Eve。
I'm starting to share my brain here.
我开始在这里分享我的想法了。
Okay, so I'll be just giving a brief overview of
好的，所以我将简要概述一下
the joint Intel-NSF ICN-WEN Center.
联合英特尔-国家科学基金会ICN-WEN中心。
It actually successfully recently completed its three year tenure.
它实际上最近成功完成了它的三年任期。
And we have two other great professors talking about it, but
我们还有两位杰出的教授将对此进行讨论，但是
I just wanna give a brief overview.
我只想简要概述一下。
So the idea, when we set up this joint center with NSF.
所以这个想法，当我们与美国国家科学基金会（NSF）共同设立这个中心时。
The idea was to explore what are some of the potential of ICN especially
这个想法是去探索ICN（信息中心网络）特别是其潜在的一些可能性。
over wireless edge networks in view of 5G and
在5G视角下，通过无线边缘网络探索。
5G+ or the new evolution of networks.
5G+或网络的新演进。
And also when we have lot many more devices and data at the edges,
而且当我们在边缘拥有更多的设备和数据时，
we wanted to see what kind of potential does ICN have.
我们想要了解ICN有什么样的潜力。
What kind of solutions can it provide to meet some of the more strict requirements?
它能提供什么样的解决方案来满足一些更严格的要求？
Whether it's latency, bandwidth, and so on.
无论是延迟、带宽等等。
And we also wanted to look at more realistic deployments or applications
我们还想研究更现实的部署或应用情况。
typically used at the edges, whether it's AR VR, autonomous driving, and so on.
通常用于边缘计算，无论是增强现实虚拟现实、自动驾驶等等。
And another important aspect of the center was
另一个中心的重要方面是
that we wanted to look at three pillars simultaneously.
我们希望同时考察三大支柱。
That is, the wireless device endpoints,
即无线设备终端，
the network infrastructure and security and privacy.
网络基础设施以及安全与隐私。
So we wanted security to be part of the story,
所以我们希望安全成为这个故事的一部分，
part of the solution and not an afterthought.
成为解决方案的一部分，而不是事后才想到的。
And I believe that the teams actually did a great job doing that.
我相信团队在这方面确实做得很好。
And we had three main projects as part of this center.
我们这个中心有三个主要的项目。
The first few that I've listed here ISAR,
我这里列出的前几个是ISAR，
the hotbed UCLA and SPLICE with the hobbit timer.
他们利用了NDN和教授们，Jeff Burke和热床UCLA以及SPLICE与霍比特计时器。
They used NDN and the professors, Jeff Burke and
他们利用了NDN和教授们，Jeff Burke和~!@#$%^&*()
Trina Chakotay will be talking about it.
Trina Chakotay将会谈论这个话题。
And I'll let them give you all the wonderful details.
我会让他们给你讲述所有精彩的细节。
The third line LSN used, it did not use NDN and use mumble at first.
第三行LSN使用的时候，它最初没有使用NDN，而是使用了mumble。
And of course there were a total of ten universities in the whole effort.
当然，在整个努力中共有十所大学参与。
And we also had a great advisory team that we put together.
我们还组建了一个很棒的顾问团队。
We had a board of advisors, Geng Wu, who I believe will be talking later today.
我们有一个顾问委员会，我相信今天晚些时候将会有耿武发言。
And of course Eve Schooler that you all know, and also Udayan Mukherjee.
我们还有几位外部顾问，你们都知道的伊夫·斯库勒，还有乌达扬·穆克吉。
And we also had a couple of external advisors, Dave Oran and
我们还有几位外部顾问，戴夫·奥兰和
Christian Tschudin.
克里斯蒂安·楚丁。
And all of them provided great feedback
他们都提供了很好的反馈。
guidance during this whole three years.
在整整三年的时间里，我们得到了很多指导。
We also had a lot of support from NSF.
我们也从美国国家科学基金会（NSF）得到了很多支持。
Darleen Fisher, Monisha Ghosh Thyaga had started it off.
Darleen Fisher，Monisha Ghosh和Thyaga一起开始了这个项目。
And also we had a good support system with an Intel management team,
我们还拥有一个由英特尔管理团队组成的良好支持系统，
and also multiple Intel champions who would attend the, we had monthly calls.
我们还有多位英特尔的冠军会参与，我们每月都会进行电话会议。
We had annual workshops and also semiannual sort of virtual workshop.
我们举办了年度研讨会，还有半年一次的线上研讨会。
And it was great interacting with the team.
与团队的互动非常棒。
At least I personally learned so much from the center and from the interactions.
我个人从中心和互动中学到了很多。
And in the last slide,
在最后一张幻灯片中，
what I wanted to mention was a little bit about our own learnings.
我想提及的是一些关于我们自己的学习心得。
I know the professors talking right after we'll be going over all the technical
我知道紧接着我们讲话的教授们将会详细讲解所有技术细节。
details and learnings that they gathered throughout the projects.
细节以及他们在项目中积累的经验教训。
But I thought it might be more useful if I talked about some of our own learnings
但我认为如果我谈论一些我们自己的学习心得可能会更有帮助。
as Intel as a research lab.
作为一个英特尔的研究实验室。
When we try to go and take these ICN solutions and
将这些ICN解决方案应用到实际中去并
incorporate them into industry solutions.
将它们整合到行业解决方案中去。
And I thought that might be something useful for everyone to hear.
我认为这可能是每个人都会觉得有用的东西。
So, one of the first things we learned is,
所以，我们学到的第一件事是，
when you talk to somebody in the business unit at Intel or
当你在英特尔的业务部门与某人交谈时，
anywhere else in the industry.
在行业的其他任何地方。
The first thing that you'll see is they compare ICN to existing systems and
首先你会看到的是，他们将ICN与现有系统进行了比较，
not just TCP-IP or TCP-IP with enhancements.
不仅仅是TCP-IP或者是经过增强的TCP-IP。
So if you say, I have a great solution for caching or video distribution.
所以如果你说，我有一个很好的缓存或视频分发解决方案。
They'll say, okay, this is the latest and greatest CDN that I have.
他们会说，好的，这是我拥有的最新最好的CDN。
And not only just the CDN now, CDNs are coming into the carrier networks and
而且现在不仅仅是CDN，CDN正在进入运营商网络并且
putting them on the base station, okay?
将它们放置在基站上，好吗？
How does it compare to that?
它与那个相比如何？
So that is a gap I felt that was there in some of the typical
所以那是我感觉在一些典型情况下存在的一个差距。
academic evaluations and how industry looks at it.
学术评价以及行业如何看待这一点。
And also a lot of times it's better at least when we are looking at
以及很多时候，至少当我们在看的时候，它会更好
solutions where ICN can provide the biggest benefits.
解决方案在哪里，ICN能提供最大的好处。
It's where to go for
往哪里去寻找
a place where there is no real solution then offer just a better solution.
一个没有真正解决方案的地方，那就提供一个更好的解决方案。
So that there is an area there is no real solution industry is actually struggling
所以在那里有一个行业实际上正在苦苦挣扎，因为没有真正的解决方案。
with it, and then you say here I have the solution.
但是当你这样做的时候，另一方面，然后你说在这里我有解决方案。
But when you do that, the other thing,
但是当你这样做的时候，另一方面，
the question we get asked is, how does it then integrate with existing systems?
我们经常被问到的问题是，它如何与现有系统集成？
So we believe that NDN has a lot of potential in dynamic edge computing and
所以我们相信NDN在动态边缘计算方面有很大的潜力，并且
orchestration.
在整合您的数据、软件以及编排方面。
When you're trying to put together your data, software and
hardware, trying to bring them together in real time and do compute.
硬件方面，尝试将它们实时整合并进行计算。
But when we started looking at that, the first question we get asked is okay we
但当我们开始研究这个问题时，我们首先被问到的问题是好的，我们
have Kubernetes we have this, that and the other.
我们有Kubernetes，我们有这个，那个和其他的。
How does it compare with that?
它与那个相比如何？
So that is one of the first things you have to do is look at existing systems.
所以首先你需要做的其中一件事就是研究现有的系统。
And even if we have a great solution, either it has to somehow coexist with it,
即使我们有了一个很好的解决方案，它也必须得以某种方式与现有系统共存。
interface with it.
它必须与之接口对接。
So in my opinion, the NDN community can make
所以在我看来，NDN社区可以产生
much bigger impact, if you start looking at these sort of verticals or
行业垂直领域或者当你开始考虑这些领域时，可以产生更大的影响。
solutions to solve specific problems and say, this is how we can do it.
为了解决特定问题，我们可以这样做，提出解决方案。
Now, you don't need to develop a full commercial solutions.
现在，你不需要开发一个完整的商业解决方案。
But even if you take an abstraction and say,
但即使你抽象地说，
this is how typically they are done in some example system.
这就是它们通常在某些示例系统中如何被完成的。
And this is how we can interface with it or
这就是我们如何与之交互的。
this is how we can make it so much better.
这就是我们如何能够让它变得更好。
So, that is kind of what I wanted to leave you with and
所以，这就是我想要给你留下的印象，还有
sort of get you thinking on a topic.
让你开始思考一个话题。
And we also believe that when it comes to dynamic composable edge computing,
我们还相信，当涉及到动态可组合边缘计算时，
there aren't many solutions out there.
目前外面的解决方案并不多。
And so it's a great area for the community to develop more support,
因此，这是一个很好的领域，社区可以在此开发更多的支持，
and also enhance the support for NDN over wireless.
同时也增强了对无线NDN的支持。
Because when we started using any NDSM,
因为当我们开始使用任何NDSM时，
We found that there were a lot of things that could be done better, for instance,
我们发现有很多事情可以做得更好，例如，
just creating dynamic faces, deleting them and so on.
只是创建动态面孔，删除它们等等。
So this concludes my talk and I wanted to leave you with some of these
所以这就结束了我的演讲，我想给你们留下一些这些内容。
points to think about and I wanted to see if there any questions.
要考虑的几个要点，我想看看是否有任何问题。
If not, Eve, I'll hand it back to you.
如果没有问题，Eve，我会把它交还给你。
>> Okay.
>> 好的。
Anybody out there who would like to means a question?
有没有人想问一个问题？
>> Maybe what is the status of the program today?
也许今天程序的状态是怎样的？
>> So we are in final stages pretty much just winding down.
所以我们基本上处于最后阶段，几乎就是在收尾了。
We had the final workshop in June this year, so at this point,
我们在今年六月举行了最后一个研讨会，所以到目前为止，
pretty much tying up some loose ends and that's pretty much it.
基本上是解决了一些尾巴问题，差不多就是这样了。
>> Catchavin can you speak to your own interest in directions for
这项工作已经向这些团队展示过了。
this work having been exposed to these teams.
>> Great question and thank you Eve.
>> 非常好的问题，谢谢你，Eve。
So as I eluded, one of the things and
所以正如我所暗示的，其中一件事情是……
it was, the last slide was sort of related to that.
它是的，最后一张幻灯片在某种程度上与此相关。
So of course, being an Intel and
所以当然，作为英特尔的一部分，
also looking at the, where we believe that there's a lot of potential for
我们也在关注那些我们认为有很大潜力的领域，
NDN is in dynamic networks and for compute.
NDN在动态网络和计算领域中的应用。
I know NDN was traditionally developed for data over fixed networks, but
我知道NDN最初是为固定网络上的数据传输开发的，但是
at least if we want to bring these solutions into industry, there are a lot
至少如果我们想将这些解决方案应用到工业领域，还有很多需要填补的空白，无论是NDN还是其他方面都需要填补。
of gaps that need to be filled, NDN or otherwise gaps need to be filled.
需要填补的空白，无论是NDN还是其他方面都需要填补。
There are so many devices, compute at the edges.
边缘处有如此多的设备，需要在边缘进行计算。
Data being generated at the edges, also resources at the edges.
边缘产生的数据，边缘也有资源。
So, we're no longer limited to just the infrastructure having resources.
所以，我们不再仅限于基础设施拥有资源。
Resources can be anywhere, it can be a zeon in a car.
资源可以存在于任何地方，它可以是汽车中的一个芯片。
It can be a laptop in a user's home or a PC and so on.
它可以是用户家中的笔记本电脑或者是个人电脑等等。
How do we bring all of these into the fold of edge computing?
我们如何将所有这些纳入边缘计算的范畴呢？
And I believe NDN has a lot of potential there.
我相信NDN在那里有很大的潜力。
So I would definitely encourage the community as well to look more into it.
所以我也肯定会鼓励社区更多地了解这个问题。
>> We have a question here.
>> 我们这里有个问题。
>> Yes?
>> 是吗？
>> I was just going to read it, from Kathy Nichols.
>> 我正打算读它，来自Kathy Nichols。
Do you have a list of your top applications
您有您最常用应用程序的列表吗？
that could use dynamic composable solutions?
那可以使用动态可组合的解决方案吗？
>> I think yeah, I think it is as the, at some instance as the question says itself.
我认为是的，我认为在某些情况下正如问题本身所说。
The applications in our mind that typically need that and
我们脑海中通常需要那个的应用情景是……
I'm sure there are more, it would be great for everyone to think about it.
我确信还有更多，如果大家都能思考一下就太好了。
Typically of course, anything is related to smart transportation.
通常情况下，任何事物都与智能交通有关。
It has mobility, it has wireless, it has mobile resources and so on,
它具有移动性，它具有无线功能，它还拥有移动资源等等，
our smart factory, cloud gaming, ARVR.
我们的智能工厂、云游戏、增强现实与虚拟现实。
So these are some of the things that come to mind, but I'm sure if you think about
所以这些是我想到的一些事情，但我相信如果你思考一下，
it, there may be others that you can come up with as well.
你也许也能想出其他的。
It's just that, if they have the competence of dynamism,
他们如果具备变革的能力，
whether the network's changing, whether there's wireless,
无论网络是否在变化，无论是否有无线连接，
whether there's mobility, just think of.
无论是否有移动性，只需想象一下。
And then along with some strict latency requirements,
它还伴随着一些严格的延迟要求，
it provides a great combination in my mind.
它在我看来提供了一个很好的结合。
>> Okay, any further questions?
好的，还有其他问题吗？
Okay, well thank you very much, Kathyayani.
好的，非常感谢你，Kathyayani。
>> Thank you.
>> 谢谢你。
We have a second talk or second presentation.
我们有第二场讲话或第二场演讲。
I'd like to introduce the topic is on SPLICE,
我想介绍的主题是SPLICE，
Secure Predictively Low-Latency Information Centric Edge for
安全预测性低延迟信息中心化边缘技术用于
next generation wireless networks.
下一代无线网络。
And the presentation will be given by Srinivas Shakkottai, who in 2007
并且演讲将由Srinivas Shakkottai主持，他于2007年
received his PhD from the University of Illinois at Urbana Champaign.
他获得了伊利诺伊大学厄巴纳-香槟分校的博士学位。
And he was a postdoctoral scholar at Stanford.
他曾是斯坦福大学的博士后研究员。
He currently is a professor at Texas A&M University in the Department of Electrical
他目前是德克萨斯A&M大学电气系的教授。
and Computer Engineering.
和计算机工程。
And his research interests include caching content distribution,
以及他的研究兴趣包括缓存内容分发，
network markets, multi agent learning and game theory,
网络市场、多智能体学习和博弈论，
wireless networks, reinforcement learning, as well as data collection and analytics.
无线网络、强化学习以及数据收集和分析。
Srinivas is the recipient, oops, somebody's typing very loudly.
Srinivas是获奖者，哎哟，有人打字声音很大。
Srinivas is the recipient of a Defense Threat Reduction agency young
Srinivas是国防威胁减少局青年
Investigator Award, and
调查员奖项，以及
NSF Career Award, as well as research awards from Cisco and Google.
NSF职业奖，以及来自思科和谷歌的研究奖项。
And a taboo, he also was received several other awards including
以及一个禁忌，他还收到了包括其他几个奖项在内的荣誉。
an outstanding professor award and an engineering genesis award.
一个杰出教授奖和一个工程创世奖。
Srinivas, it's all yours.
斯里尼瓦斯，这全归你了。
>> Thank you, thank you all for being here.
>> 谢谢，感谢大家的到来。
So, I'll try to keep it reasonably concise.
所以，我会尽量保持简洁。
This is actually the combination of three years of research by several universities,
这实际上是几所大学三年研究的结合。
several researchers.
几位研究人员。
So SPLICE stands for, Secure Predictive Low-Latency Information Centric Edge.
所以SPLICE代表的是，安全预测低延迟信息中心化边缘。
And the goal was to work it into next generation wireless.
目标是将其融入下一代无线技术中。
So that's the kind of ultimate aim.
所以那就是最终的目标。
So this project was across multiple universities, five of them.
所以这个项目是跨越了多所大学，一共五所。
From Texas A&M, P R Kumar, and I'm giving this talk essentially for him.
来自德克萨斯A&M大学的P R Kumar，基本上是我代表他来做这次演讲。
So there's Kumar, myself, and I-H.Hou from Texas A&M.
所以有Kumar，我自己，还有来自德克萨斯A&M大学的I-H.Hou。
There's Shroff and Attila Errol Masse from Ohio State,
有Shroff和来自俄亥俄州立大学的Attila Errol Masse，
Rheumatoid Charles Murray from Illinois, Alisa Bertino, and
伊利诺伊州的风湿病专家查尔斯·默里，Alisa Bertino，以及
Charlie Hu from Purdue, and Patrick Rowley from WashU St. Louis.
普渡大学的查理·胡和圣路易斯华盛顿大学的帕特里克·罗利。
So if you look at this team,
所以如果你看看这个团队，
we are composed of folks doing wireless security scheduling, and
我们由从事无线安全调度的人员组成，以及
Patrick going in was the only person strongly invested in NDN specifically.
帕特里克是唯一一个特别投入于NDN（命名数据网络）的人。
And so, this has been a good deal of a learning experience for
因此，这对我们其他人来说也是一个很好的学习经历。
the rest of us as well.
对我们其他人来说也是如此。
Because we went in thinking that NDN as a very interesting
因为我们开始时认为NDN是一个非常有趣的
kind of scheme of things, but with little experience with actually working with it.
但实际上对它的工作经验很少。
And when we came away, we were kind of solidly invested in the functionalities
当我们离开时，我们已经相当深入地投入到这些功能中了。
deploys, as well as being able to contribute to its enhancement.
部署以及能够对其增强做出贡献。
So what was the point of this project?
那么这个项目的意义是什么？
Our goal was when we went in,
我们进入时的目标是
we were trying to understand what is a worthwhile kind of application?
我们试图理解什么样的应用是值得的？
Containing, alluded to this as well, what is a worthwhile application at
包含了这个观点，什么是值得的应用？
the wireless edge which doesn't exist today in some sense?
无线边缘在某种意义上今天并不存在吗？
And which is kind of very clearly obvious going forward.
而这在未来将变得非常明显。
And we were kind of thinking about applications
我们在考虑应用方面。
in that you're doing control of systems over wireless networks.
在这方面，你正在通过无线网络进行系统控制。
So in many of these control systems,
所以在许多这样的控制系统中，
what you wish to do is kind of reconstruct a physical or virtual theme.
你希望做的是在某种程度上重建一个物理的或虚拟的主题。
For example, if you think about autonomous vehicles,
例如，如果你考虑自动驾驶汽车，
you have some vehicles with Lidar, some with cameras, some with radar, etc.
你有一些车辆配备了激光雷达，一些配备了摄像头，还有一些配备了雷达等等。
And what the vehicles are interested in is an abstraction of the physical field,
而这些车辆感兴趣的是对物理场的一种抽象，
what is located where, where are roads, people bicycles, etc.
位于何处，哪里有道路，人们、自行车等。
So you're interested in reconstructing a physical dynamic field at all these nodes
所以你对于在所有这些节点重建一个物理动态场感兴趣。
and then they wish to take some control action.
然后他们希望采取一些控制行动。
Similarly, if you think of virtual reality, we were thinking specifically of
同样地，如果你考虑虚拟现实，我们特别在想
virtual reality multiplayer gaming, in which again, you have a virtual field.
虚拟现实多人游戏，在这种游戏中，你又有了一个虚拟的场地。
You've got all these monsters and walls and etc, all happening.
你会遇到各种怪物、墙壁等等，这些都是在游戏中发生的事情。
You're events which are going on which is who is where,
你会遇到谁在哪里的情况，这些都是正在发生的事件。
who is shooting at what, etc.
谁在射击什么，等等。
Or if it's a driving game, where these vehicles are moving, etc.
或者如果是一款赛车游戏，这些车辆在哪里移动，等等。
And that virtual field needs to be reconstructed
而那个虚拟场景需要被重建。
with minimal delay at all the agents, the game players in question, right?
在所有代理商这里，几乎没有任何延迟，对吧，游戏玩家们？
In both these if you think about it, there is a good deal of commonality,
在这两种情况下，如果你仔细想想，它们之间有很多共同点，
you want a similar reconstruction at all these agents in terms of the field and
你希望在这些代理人方面进行类似的重建，以便于领域内。
what the things are where.
物品分布在哪里。
So there is a good deal of correlation across user information requirements.
因此，在用户信息需求之间存在很大的相关性。
And so what really the user or
因此，用户或应用程序真正想要的是专注于提取所需的信息。
the application really wants is to focus on extracting the desired information.
应用程序真正想要的是专注于提取所需的信息。
For example, in virtual reality, there is a so
例如，在虚拟现实中，有一个所谓的动作到光子延迟要求。
called motion to photon latency requirement.
称为动作到光子延迟要求。
In the sense that to move your head,
在这个意义上，移动你的头部，
you need a different viewpoint within roughly 12 to 15 milliseconds.
你需要在大约12到15毫秒内改变一个不同的视角。
So that's pretty strict, because within that that time duration,
所以这是相当严格的，因为在那个时间段内，
you need to kind of identify what the user wants,
你需要某种程度上识别用户想要什么，
to render that particular viewpoint, shift that viewpoint.
要呈现那个特定的视角，就得转换视角。
If you're doing wirelessly, the viewpoint, the information corresponding to it, has
要通过无线方式进行的话，相应的视角信息必须要有
to wind up at the user headset, it has to be uncompressed and displayed to the user.
要在用户的头戴设备上结束，它必须被解压缩并向用户显示。
And if you increase the latency, user start getting nauseated, etc.
如果你增加了延迟，用户开始感到恶心等不适症状。
Which is why really, when you look at the systems like Oculus, they have got a big
这就是为什么当你真正看看像Oculus这样的系统时，他们拥有一个大型的
rendering engine, a big edge compute box sitting in your living room or wherever.
渲染引擎，一个大型的边缘计算盒子放置在你的客厅或其他地方。
And you've got a cable connecting the headset to the box so that you have very,
并且你有一根电缆将头戴设备连接到盒子上，这样你就拥有非常
very low latency.
非常低的延迟。
Now if you want to cut that cable, if you want to make everything wireless,
如果你想要剪断那根电缆，如果你想要让所有东西都变成无线的，
that imposes quite a lot of constrictions on the information requirement as well as
那对信息需求以及其他方面施加了相当多的限制。
the wireless network itself.
无线网络本身。
Which is why we are focusing on controllable wireless delivery modalities.
这就是为什么我们专注于可控的无线传输方式。
How do we change the wireless network itself?
我们如何改变无线网络本身？
Primarily we'll be focusing on MAC scheduling algorithms,
我们主要将专注于MAC调度算法，
keeping application performance and definitely security in mind.
在考虑应用性能的同时，绝对不能忽视安全性。
In terms of security,
在安全方面，
we were interested in the wireless angle in terms of connectivity.
我们对于连接性方面的无线角度感兴趣。
As well as the information angle in terms of encryption decryption in the NDN
以及在NDN中关于加密解密的信息角度。
context.
上下文。
So in that context, we were trying to build a kind of system from
所以在那个上下文中，我们试图从头开始构建一种系统，在这种系统中我们可以基本上控制每一层。
the ground up in which we can essentially control every layer.
从头开始，在这种系统中我们可以基本上控制每一层。
Ideally using a combination of kind of custom software and hardware.
理想情况下，使用一种自定义软件和硬件的组合。
So if you look at the lowest layer here, the blue one,
所以如果你看这里最底层的蓝色那层，
it is basically the wireless angle.
它基本上是无线通信的角度。
So what we've got there is a software defined radio in which we have full access
所以我们得到的是一个软件定义的无线电，在这个无线电中我们有完全的访问权限。
to the complete fine MAC, right?
我们可以完全控制到精细的MAC层，对吗？
And going up into the network stack,
我们还得深入到网络栈的上层。
you have the host machine in which you have the network stack as well.
您有一台主机，其中也包含了网络栈。
So in other words, these USRPs are the software defined radios connected to
换句话说，这些USRP是连接到软件定义无线电的。
a kind of a controllerless scheme of things which is based on LabVIEW, right?
这是一种基于LabVIEW的无控制器方案，对吗？
And in which we basically can do MAC based changes in MAC scheduling etc.
并且在这个基础上，我们基本上可以对MAC调度等进行基于MAC地址的更改。
And we connected up this UDP indicator there,
我们在那里连接了这个UDP指示器，
is a local connection within a machine, it's not a TCP IP over the air.
它是机器内部的本地连接，并不是通过空气传输的TCP IP。
It is only UDP within to connect LabVIEW to the local host.
它仅使用UDP在本地主机内连接LabVIEW。
And then onwards we have the NFD stack and the applications.
接下来我们有了NFD堆栈和应用程序。
So essentially what this is, if you will, is a kind of pure or semi pure information
所以本质上，如果你愿意的话，这是一种纯粹或半纯粹的信息。
centric architecture wherein TCP IP is actually not even required, right?
集中式架构中，实际上甚至不需要TCP/IP，对吧？
As I said, we use that UDP for
正如我所说，我们使用UDP来进行
a local connection because LabVIEW is capable of local UDP sockets.
因为LabVIEW能够处理本地UDP套接字，所以这是一种本地连接。
But the end to end from the server to the client is not a TCP IP connection at all.
但是从服务器到客户端的端到端连接根本不是TCP/IP连接。
The only thing which is connecting them are MAC IDs.
连接它们的唯一东西是MAC ID。
So the USRP uses a MAC ID and the other USRP uses this MAC ID
因此，一个USRP使用MAC ID，另一个USRP使用这个MAC ID。
to determine where it is coming from and who it is destined for.
为了确定它来自哪里以及它的目的地是哪里。
So that's our general architecture.
所以这就是我们的总体架构。
And I want to spend the next few minutes discussing what we attained or
接下来的几分钟我想讨论一下我们实现了什么或者
what are the goals of each level of this.
这个的每个层级的目标是什么。
And how we kind of went towards this ultimate goal of field reconstruction and
我们是如何朝着这个最终目标即场景重建迈进的。
control.
控制。
So if you look at this bottom most layer,
所以如果你看这最底层，
the question is can we use an off the shelf wireless communication scheme?
问题是我们能否使用现成的无线通信方案？
For example, there is WiFi, which is essentially based on
例如，有WiFi，它本质上是基于
carrier sense multiple access back offs, so distributed.
载波侦听多路访问退避，因此是分布式的。
And LTE which is more scheduled.
而LTE则是更加有计划的调度。
Now if you want to attend latency guarantees, recollect this business of
现在，如果你想要确保低延迟，记住这个问题，
virtual reality requiring about 15 or so milliseconds latency.
虚拟现实需要大约15毫秒左右的延迟。
Essentially, we calculated that if you need that kind of latency,
本质上，我们计算出如果你需要那种延迟，
the rendering is going to take quite a while, roughly four or five milliseconds,
渲染将会花费相当长的时间，大约四到五毫秒，
then there's compression.
然后是压缩。
It turns out that the wireless angle, the one half wireless,
原来无线角度，那个一半无线，
you have about two ish milliseconds, maybe three.
你大约有两毫秒左右的时间，也许三毫秒。
So essentially we needed a scheme wherein we can guarantee per packet latencies
所以本质上我们需要一个方案，能够保证每个数据包的延迟时间。
of less than two to three milliseconds, right?
而WiFi存在的问题是，由于它是CSMA，只要有关键流量存在，就无法保证每个数据包的延迟时间少于两到三毫秒，对吗？
Now the problem with WiFi is, given the critical flows exists because it's CSMA,
现在WiFi存在的问题是，鉴于关键流量的存在，因为它是CSMA，
you have no guarantee whatsoever.
你根本没有任何保证。
If you look at LTE 4G, basically, the frame length is ten milliseconds.
如果你看一下LTE 4G，基本上，帧长度是十毫秒。
But the problem is, when you transmit a packet,
但问题在于，当你传输一个数据包时，
the ack comes back either as a bundled ack, or
确认应答要么作为捆绑式确认返回，要么
you have to schedule the ack, which is seven milliseconds away at the minimum.
你必须安排确认应答，其最短时间为七毫秒。
So in other words, LTE is not capable of this low latency kind of scheme.
换句话说，LTE无法实现这种低延迟的方案。
And remember, when we were doing this 5G was in its infancy.
而且要记住，当我们开始研究这个的时候，5G还处于起步阶段。
Indeed, even now, 5G deployments with ultra low latency are fairly minimal.
的确，即便是现在，具有超低延迟的5G部署也相当有限。
So essentially what we were looking for
所以本质上我们在寻找的是
was our own custom NDN friendly ultra low latency scheme, right?
我们自己定制的、适用于NDN的超低延迟方案，对吗？
And so the edge of information has to decide to do this idea.
信息边缘必须决定采纳这个想法。
That essentially we are doing field reconstruction.
我们本质上在进行场的重构。
And the value of the field is as good as how it represents reality.
场的价值在于它对现实的准确反映。
So if you're looking at autonomous driving, if a certain object has moved and
所以如果你在研究自动驾驶，如果某个物体已经移动了，
you don't know about it, well your field,
你对此一无所知，好吧，你的领域，
your perception of reality is different from reality itself.
你对现实的感知与现实本身是不同的。
And this difference between reality and
你对现实的感知与现实本身之间的差异
your perception of it is the edge of information.
你对它的感知就是信息的边缘。
So you want to minimize this edge of information.
所以你想要尽可能减少这个信息的边缘。
This applies even in virtual reality regime,
这甚至也适用于虚拟现实环境中，
in the sense that there is a monster in front of you or next to you, etc.
在这种意义上，就像你面前或你旁边有一个怪物一样。
Where is the monster as far as the canonical virtual world is concerned
在规范虚拟世界中，怪物在哪里？
versus where is it with respect to where you are, I mean, your perception of it?
那与你所在之处相比，怪物在哪里呢？我是说，你对它的感知如何？
So you want to minimize that that difference in perception, right?.
所以你想要尽量减少那种感知上的差异，对吗？
Now we said that there are multiple users and so there's correlation across them.
现在我们说到有多个用户，因此它们之间存在相关性。
So we wanted to build in some level of multicast support.
所以我们想要在某种程度上支持多播功能。
And indeed NDN awareness in the sense that we need to tie this in into NDN.
确实，我们需要将其与NDN结合起来，以实现对NDN的认识。
So that the NDN packets that are issued, requests, interest packets and
因此，发出的NDN数据包，请求，兴趣包等
the responses etc are kind of cleanly integrated into the wireless layer.
这些响应等在无线层中被整合得相当干净利落。
So that they can reveal in some sense what their latency requirements are etc, and
因此他们可以在某种程度上揭示出他们的延迟需求等信息。
we can integrate it and support it.
我们可以将其整合并提供支持。
So I'm gonna give you one slide on one of the major results.
所以我将用一张幻灯片给你们介绍一个主要的结果。
So essentially, the very first one is what I'm going to talk about.
所以基本上，我要讲的第一个就是这个。
In which way we instantiated, we developed delay scheduling algorithms which
我们开发了延迟调度算法，通过这种方式实例化，
maximize the delay sensitive throughput, we call this timely throughput.
我们将其称为及时吞吐量，以最大化对延迟敏感的吞吐量。
And we basically actually instantiated it on USRPs.
我们基本上实际上是在USRPs上实例化了它。
After that there were several papers on actually integrating it into various
之后有几篇论文实际上是关于将其集成到各种不同的
regimes.
体制中。
And the last one was actually that since we had this platform where we could
而最后一个实际上是因为我们有这样一个平台，在那里我们可以
control the system at various different layers, we actually built a RL platform,
控制系统在各种不同层面上，我们实际上构建了一个RL（强化学习）平台，
a reinforcement learning platform to do auto configuration.
一个用于自动配置的强化学习平台。
So that was the very end of this, which appeared last year.
这就是去年出现的这件事情的最后部分。
But I just want to tell you about the capacity region,
但我只是想告诉你关于容量区域的情况，
I think, by our low latency scheduling algorithms.
我认为，通过我们的低延迟调度算法。
So what this diagram shows is basically the real time versus the non real time.
所以这张图表基本上展示的是实时与非实时的对比。
Traffic supportable simultaneously by a wireless channel of 20 megahertz, right.
无线信道在20兆赫频宽下能同时支持的流量。
So the leftmost one is our scheduling scheme.
因此，最左边的一个是我们的调度方案。
Wherein you notice that it attains the full convex region.
其中你会注意到它达到了完整的凸区域。
Whereas other schemes such as just longest few first, max weight basically, or
而其他的方案，比如仅仅是最长的几个优先，基本上是最大权重，或者
random policies or round robin etc are unable to attain.
随机策略或者轮询等都无法达到的。
So basically, we're able to show that analytically valuable kind of takeaways in
所以基本上，我们能够展示出在分析上有价值的收获。
terms of the scheduling algorithms actually have an impact in reality.
调度算法的条款实际上在现实中有影响。
You're able to support a larger region of operations.
您能够支持更大范围的操作区域。
Now, moving up to the NDN scheme of things and caching.
现在，让我们谈谈NDN模式和缓存的事宜。
Essentially our our thought process with the NDN was that
本质上，我们对NDN的思考是这样的
one big advantage that NDN provides is information reuse.
NDN提供的一个重大优势是信息复用。
That is it is cached at multiple locations in the content stores that are available.
因此，它被缓存在多个可用的内容存储位置中。
And so essentially can be utilized, one,
因此，本质上可以被利用，一来，
this this kind of stream of names going by because you see the names.
这种名字的流动，因为你看到了这些名字。
Can you predict what name will be requested next essentially by
你能预测出下一个被请求的名字吗，基本上通过
multiple streams as these names go by?
能否因此提前确定可能会被请求的内容，通过这些名字流转的多个渠道？
And can you therefore determine in advance what might be requested and
能否因此提前确定可能会被请求的内容，
cache it in advance?
能否因此提前缓存它？
Now of course NDN is opportunistic, we want it to be and
现在当然了，NDN是机会主义的，我们希望它是这样的，并且
make it basically predictable, right?
使其基本上可预测，对吧？
So the scheme of things they were we wanted to have a way of doing proactive
所以我们想要一个主动的行事方案。
requesting.
我们需要在NDN中构建这一功能。
We needed to build this into NDN.
So we had some NFD modifications to allow this to happen.
所以我们对NFD进行了一些修改以实现这一功能。
And furthermore, we wanted to actually provide latency guarantees via smart
并且，我们还想通过智能手段提供延迟保证。
caching algorithms which can actually prefetch the items which are needed.
缓存算法能够实际预取所需的项目。
Again we need wireless awareness because the link may be lossy, etc.
因此我们需要无线感知，因为连接可能会有丢包等问题。
So identifying which links to focus on for
因此，确定应该重点关注哪些链接至关重要。
such predictions and how much you can do prediction versus opportunistic, etc.
这些预测以及你能进行多少预测对比于机会主义行为等问题。
Are questions which we have to deal with with respect to the wireless link.
这些是我们必须处理的与无线链接相关的问题。
So in this context, we had a whole bunch of work.
所以在这种情况下，我们有一大堆工作要做。
The first three are more related to NFD modifications, our
前三个更多地与NFD的修改有关，我们的
own kind of flavor of NFD, which basically allows you to kind of prerequest stuff.
我们自己的NFD风格，基本上允许你预先请求一些东西。
Because if you think about it,
因为如果你仔细想想，
NFD by itself is not really issuing interests of its own, right.
NFD本身并不真正发行它自己的利益，对吧。
And so what we did was we basically stuck in an algorithm as it were a small module,
于是我们所做的就是基本上插入了一个算法，就像是一个小模块，
which looks at the stream of interest going by, and
它观察着流过的利息流动，以及
issues interest natively from NFT itself.
问题利息本质上源自NFT本身。
So that these interest when they're satisfied will come and
因此，当这些利息得到满足时，它们将会来临。
sit in the caching, the content store of the loaded question.
坐在缓存中，已加载问题的内容存储。
And so are available closer to the end user even before the end user actually
请求数据甚至在最终用户实际需要之前，就已经更靠近最终用户而可用了。
issues of interest.
感兴趣的问题。
So, essentially we worked on proactive requests.
所以，基本上我们致力于主动请求。
This was mostly focused on by the folks at washu.
这主要是由沃什大学的人员所关注的。
Then we use some of these ideas for enabling these predictive requests,
然后我们利用这些想法来启用这些预测性请求，
as I said to NFD modifications.
正如我所说，关于NFD的修改。
Another strain of thought was, if you're really interested in low latency,
另一种思考方式是，如果你真的对低延迟很感兴趣，
perhaps the NFD forwarding scheme of things needs optimization.
也许需要对NFD转发方案进行优化。
And so, some folks actually worked on that kind of
因此，有些人实际上已经在这方面进行了工作。
evaluating different forwarding schemes including hardware based forwarding.
评估了不同的转发方案，包括基于硬件的转发。
In order to reduce the latency of NDN Forwarding,
为了减少NDN转发的延迟，
specifically when you scale up to larger amounts of traffic, right?
具体来说，就是当你扩大到更大量的流量时，对吧？
On the Caching side,
在缓存方面，
we had several fundamental results, specifically based on unreliable channels.
我们得到了几个基本结果，特别是基于不可靠信道的研究。
We found several counterintuitive results on when you should cache and
我们发现了几个违反直觉的结果，关于你应该何时进行缓存。
how much you should distribute your cache memories.
你应该如何分配你的缓存内存。
So that's where I'll stop with respect to this.
那么关于这个问题，我就讲到这里。
An implementation, which we had to do with virtual reality.
这是我们必须使用虚拟现实来实现的。
This was integration of the whole system, wherein you have the VR headset,
这是整个系统的集成，其中你有VR头盔，
you have caches of NDN basically, as well as the wireless channel underneath.
你有NDN的缓存，以及底层的无线信道。
And this is not a video it's just a frame, please.
这不是一个视频，它只是一个画面，请注意。
Basically we were able to show I think you should be able to see it on your screens.
基本上我们能够展示出来，我认为你们应该能在屏幕上看到它。
The top left is with predictive, we are able to support a much higher rate of high
左上角是带有预测功能的，我们能够支持更高频率的高清分辨率帧。
resolution frames than the bottom right, which is should look kind of grainy.
所以你在玩游戏时实际上可以看到，右下角应该看起来有点颗粒感。
So you actually see this as you play the game,
所以你在玩游戏时实际上可以看到这一点，
you can see that a good deal more is at a much higher resolution,
你可以看到相当多的内容分辨率更高。
you can pretty much make sure that most of them are at high resolution.
你几乎可以确信它们中的大多数都是高分辨率的。
Only a few will be at the lower resolution.
只有少数会是低分辨率的。
So that was kind of so we were able to improve the end user quality of experience
所以这就是我们能够提高最终用户体验质量的原因。
by tying in caching as well as the wireless.
通过结合缓存以及无线技术。
And so the final thing I just mentioned the VR App,
所以我最后提到的就是VR应用，
the high level goal of VR App in general was to cut the cord.
总体而言，VR应用的高级目标是实现无线化。
So when I began this talk I talked about essentially Oculus, and
所以当我开始这个演讲时，我主要谈论的是Oculus，以及
the fact that you need a cable between the edge rendering box and your headset.
事实上，你需要一根电缆将边缘渲染盒子和你的头戴设备连接起来。
The goal was to actually eliminate that via smart wireless scheduling and
目标实际上是通过智能无线调度来消除这种情况。
prefetching.
预取。
So that via the use of NDN, basically for
所以通过使用NDN，基本上是为了
this kind of communication, right.
这种通信方式，对。
Now finally, of course, we needed this whole system to be secured by design.
现在最终，当然，我们需要这整个系统从设计上就是安全的。
So essentially, we needed the questions of access control security and
所以本质上，我们需要解决访问控制安全问题和
information security.
信息安全。
And the information security,
信息安全，
the first two bullet points there, indicate that we need latency guarantees.
前两个要点表明，我们需要延迟保证。
Because we do not have infinite time we only have about 14 or
因为我们没有无限的时间，我们大约只有14或
so milliseconds before the next frame shows up at the headset.
所以在下一帧显示在头显上之前，我们大约只有14或15毫秒的时间。
So, essentially the if we realized we can't afford to spend two or
因此，本质上如果我们意识到我们不能花费两个或者
three milliseconds in encryption decryption.
我们在加密解密中不能花费三毫秒。
So, we wanted lightweight encryption schemes, and
因此，我们需要轻量级的加密方案，
that was pretty much the focus of Lisa Martino's group.
这基本上是丽莎·马蒂诺小组的关注焦点。
As well as looking at essentially access control methods, she focused primarily
她主要关注的是基本的访问控制方法。
on LTE because we realize going forward 5G is going to be based on LTE.
因为我们意识到未来的5G将会基于LTE，所以我们专注于LTE。
And many of our scheduling algorithms etcetera,
在很多方面，我们的调度算法等等，
would have a natural home in 5G in some sense.
在某种意义上，会在5G中找到一个自然的归宿。
Although as things have developed over the past three years, it's
尽管在过去三年的发展中，事情是这样的，
even Wi-Fi has moved towards a scheduling based scheme, Wi-Fi 6 and so on.
即使Wi-Fi也已经转向了基于调度的方案，比如Wi-Fi 6等。
I love scheduling, so it's kind of interesting that both Wi-Fi and
我喜欢调度，所以Wi-Fi和
LTE or 5G are moving strongly towards the scheduled scheme of things as
LTE或5G正在大力推进计划化的方案，因为
opposed to random access.
相对于随机接入而言。
So the main results from the security side.
所以主要的结果来自于安全方面。
The first few all have to do with access security, essentially looking for schemes,
前几项主要与接入安全有关，本质上是在寻找方案，
which are kind of poorly developed with respect to the security angle in LTE.
它们在LTE中的安全角度来说发展得相当不充分。
The latter few are related to essentially signature schemes, encryption, decryption
后面几个主要与签名方案、加密、解密有关。
and that's really what I want to focus on as my kind of candidates slide.
这正是我想要专注的候选人展示方面。
So this basically indicates, >> If you could surely fast if you could
所以这基本上意味着，>>如果你能肯定地快速地如果你能
wrap up shortly, that would be great.
如果你能尽快结束，那就太好了。
>> I'm done with the last slide basically.
>> 我基本上完成了最后一张幻灯片。
>> Okay.
>> 好的。
>> Oops, sorry.
>> 哎呀，抱歉。
So essentially what we had, we wanted to say that we had lightweight signature
所以本质上我们想要说的是，我们拥有轻量级签名
schemes, wherein you can actually encrypt decrypt much more quickly.
方案中，你实际上可以更快地进行加密解密。
So I have a slide on that actual system how it looked in terms of a access point,
所以我有一个幻灯片是关于那个实际系统的样子，就是从接入点的角度来看的，
and multiple hosts.
和多个主机。
And finally, this has to do with a little bit more on the system architecture, but
最后，这还涉及到系统架构方面的一些内容，但是
I'll wrap up there and say thank you.
我就说到这里，谢谢大家。
>> Terrific, thank you.
>> 太棒了，谢谢。
Are there any questions?
有什么问题吗？
>> It says somebody I need a highlight.
>> 它说有人需要一个重点。
I don't want the paint.
我不想要油漆。
>> I don't know what the highlight is either [LAUGH].
我也不知道重点是什么[笑]。
But actually, can you tell us where the work is going next?
但实际上，你能告诉我们接下来的工作将怎么进行吗？
>> So one aspect is we asked for a no cost extension and
我们申请了无成本延期，这是其中一个方面，
we got some funds from the power testbeds
我们从电力测试平台获得了一些资金。
to try out some of these ideas over the air over reasonable ranges.
尝试通过空中在合理的距离内试验这些想法。
So we basically as far as this extension to power is a platform for
所以我们基本上就是将这个扩展作为一个电力平台。
advanced wireless research.
我们在那里所做的是与犹他测试基地进行先进无线研究。
And what we're doing there is working with the Utah test bed
我们在那里所做的是与犹他测试基地进行合作。
wherein they have got USRPs and SRSNT operating all of them.
其中他们有USRP和SRSNT操作所有这些。
Where we want to try out this combination of low latency scheduling and
我们希望尝试将低延迟调度与此相结合。
NDN with the idea that if you think of things like autonomous vehicles and so on.
我们将NDN与自动驾驶汽车等概念结合起来。
You are going to be operating them in the field, with these long range links.
您将在野外使用这些远程链接来操作它们。
And the question was what kind of performance gains can we get using NDN for
我们可以通过使用NDN获得哪些类型的性能提升？
as a field reconstruction in the context of autonomous vehicles.
作为自动驾驶车辆环境中的领域重构。
That is one one train of thought which is continuing.
这是一个持续发展的思路。
This same idea we believe is valuable also in
我们也相信这个想法在……方面同样有价值。
I think that was mentioned in the last session as well.
我认为那在上一次会议中也提到过。
Essentially, it looks like it's the whole concept of ICN and
从本质上来说，看起来它是整个ICN（信息中心网络）的概念，以及
NDN specifically seems to be quite valuable in the context of sharing
NDN在共享背景下似乎特别有价值。
information with a lot of commonality in the context of autonomous vehicles.
信息在自动驾驶车辆的背景下具有很多共性。
So that's
~!@#$%^&*()
something which we think is valuable and something to look forward too.
我们认为有价值并值得期待的事物。
>> Thank you very much for your insights.
>> 非常感谢您的见解。
That was terrific.
那真是太棒了。
>> Thank you.
>> 谢谢。
>> Okay, we're gonna hand over the floor to Jeff Burke, who's gonna speak to us.
>> 好的，我们将把讲话权交给Jeff Burke，他将向我们发言。
He's going to give us an update on ICN-Enabled Secure Edge Networking
他将向我们提供有关ICN支持的安全边缘网络的最新进展。
with Augmented Reality the ICE-AR project.
他将会介绍增强现实技术在ICE-AR项目中的应用。
And for those of you who don't know him already,
对于那些还不认识他的人来说，
Jeff Burke is a Professor in Residence at the UCLA Department of Theater.
Jeff Burke 是加州大学洛杉矶分校戏剧系的常驻教授。
He co directs REMAP, the Center for Research and
他共同指导了REMAP，即研究与工程媒介表现的中心。
Engineering Medium Performance.
工程媒介表现联合中心，这是加州大学洛杉矶分校戏剧、电影与电视学院的一部分。
Joint Center of the UCLA School of Theater, Film and
加州大学洛杉矶分校戏剧、电影与电视学院联合中心
Television and the Samueli School of Engineering.
电视与塞缪利工程学院。
REMAP has conducted application research in NDN since 2010,
REMAP自2010年以来一直在进行NDN的应用研究，
and Jeff is a COPI in the NSF Intel Supported ICE-AR Program.
杰夫是NSF Intel支持的ICE-AR项目的合作主要研究者。
All yours, Jeff.
全权交给你了，杰夫。
>> Great, thanks to you.
太好了，多亏了你。
So this is collaborative work by the PI's that are listed in
所以这是列在幻灯片底部的负责人们共同完成的工作，他们中的几位也参与了这次通话。
the bottom of this slide and several of them are also on this call.
这张幻灯片的底部列出了他们的名字，其中几位也参与了这次通话。
So at the end if you have questions, they're here as well.
如果你们最后有问题，他们也在这里。
I am going to give a quick overview of the ICE-AR program,
我将快速概述ICE-AR项目，
and talk a bit about the lessons that we've learned.
并谈谈我们学到的一些教训。
And these are things that we've gone back and forth internally on quite a bit,
这些都是我们内部反复讨论过很多次的事情，
both to share with Intel and NSF, and now with you.
既是为了与英特尔和美国国家科学基金会共享，现在也与您分享。
There are four research thrusts, one in applications that really led to API and
这里有四个研究重点，其中一个是在应用领域，这个领域真正引领了API的发展，并且
library development as a big part of the project
作为项目的重要组成部分的库开发
as we navigated what exactly are applications needed.
在我们探索究竟需要哪些应用程序时。
One on security at the edge, one on information-centric wireless,
一个关于边缘安全性的，一个关于信息中心无线技术的，
so the impact of a data centric NDN based approach on lower layer
因此，基于数据中心的NDN方法对底层的影响。
wireless technology in this edge context.
无线技术在这种边缘环境中。
And then the use of acceleration as a service, and
以及作为一项服务的加速应用，还有
all of these were driven by the use of augmented reality and
所有这些都是由增强现实的使用所推动的，以及
layered mixed reality to drive research on NDN at the wireless edge.
分层混合现实技术推动了无线边缘处的NDN（命名数据网络）研究。
So on the website, there is a significant amount of code and
因此，在网站上有大量的代码和
more detailed publications.
更详细的出版物。
I'm gonna go pretty quickly through everything here.
我会很快地讲解这里的所有内容。
And so there's a lot more of a technical detail there.
所以那里有更多的技术细节。
So the original driver was decentralized augmented reality.
所以最初的驱动力是去中心化的增强现实。
So the basic idea is that for AR in the future,
所以基本的想法是，对于未来的AR来说，
we may move from applications that are centralized.
我们可能会从集中式的应用程序转变过来。
And they're delivered in a stovepipe context, both for the apps and
并且它们是在一个独立的上下文中交付的，无论是对于应用程序还是
the content to a decentralized approach, where individuals share their context,
内容采用了一种去中心化的方法，其中个人分享他们的上下文，
things like location, camera view, and so on.
诸如位置、摄像头视角等信息。
And in return, get content offers from many sources.
并且作为回报，从多个来源获得内容提供。
And that there are edge processing nodes that participate in both
并且有边缘处理节点参与其中。
the calculation of the context or figuring out a deeper notion
计算上下文或者理解更深层的概念。
of context from the raw sensor readings on the phone, and
从手机上的原始传感器读数中提取上下文信息，并且
also then delivering customized content to an eventual AR experience.
还将定制内容传送至最终的增强现实体验中。
And over the course of the project, I think we shifted on the application side
在项目过程中，我认为我们在应用方面进行了调整。
to not only looking at AR, but really looking at a more general shift in media
不仅仅关注增强现实技术，而是真正考虑到媒体的更广泛转变。
and experience and delivery from an old model in which computation was kind of
在旧模式中，计算在某种程度上是
isolated at each stage of the production process.
在生产过程的每个阶段都是孤立的。
From envisioning the media, to making it, to delivering it, and experiencing it,
从构想媒体，到制作媒体，再到传递媒体，以及体验媒体，
to really a realtime model that's inspired by certainly the way the web works.
转变为一个真正的实时模型，这种模型无疑是受到了网络运作方式的启发。
But also now, game engines, and some of the realtime 3D rendering tools
但现在，游戏引擎和一些实时3D渲染工具也在影响着增强现实、虚拟现实和电影制作等领域。
that are influencing AR VR cinematic production and so
正在影响着增强现实、虚拟现实和电影制作等领域。
on, which presents a lot of interesting opportunities for edge computation,
在这方面，为边缘计算带来了许多有趣的机会，
in which media is customized at the last possible moment.
在这种情况下，媒体内容在最后可能的时刻被定制。
So the first of the ICE-AR thrusts was this application focus,
因此，ICE-AR项目的首个重点是这个应用程序的焦点。
and I'm actually not gonna discuss too much the AR and
我实际上不打算过多讨论增强现实技术。
MR integration tests that were really driving our hands on experimentation.
MR集成测试真正推动了我们进行实际操作实验。
And just wanna focus for this presentation on four outcomes,
并且只想在这次演讲中专注于四个成果，
in terms of new APIs and libraries for the community.
在新的API和社区库方面。
The first is called the Common Name Library, NDN-CNL.
第一个被称为通用名称库，NDN-CNL。
And this is a collection oriented API for NDN that kind of moves one layer up
这是一个面向NDN的集合导向型API，它在某种程度上提升了一个层次。
from the interest data exchange that most of the existing APIs that handle.
它提供了一种替代基于套接字的思维方式，这种方式专注于处理大多数现有API所涉及的兴趣数据交换。
And presents an alternative to a socket based way of thinking that focuses on
它提供了一种替代基于套接字的思维方式，这种方式专注于处理
name based collections as the API for the application itself.
名称基于集合作为应用程序本身的API。
The second was a integration of our previous work on realtime
第二个是我们之前关于实时工作的整合。
video into a visual programming language called touch designer.
这被称为TouchNDN，所以你会看到一点将视频转换成一种名为Touch Designer的视觉编程语言。
This was called TouchNDN, so you'll see a little
这被称为TouchNDN，所以你会看到一点
bit in the video that probably is not playing very smoothly for you.
在视频中的一小部分可能没有为你播放得很流畅。
But you get a rough idea of his visual programming environment for
但你大概了解了他的视觉编程环境。
experimenting with data centric media.
实验数据中心媒体。
Then on the lower right is a stack diagram for NDN-Lite, which is the latest
然后在右下角是NDN-Lite的堆栈图，这是最新的
generation IoT framework kind of taking into account the needs of both easy and
世代物联网框架在考虑到既要简单又要满足需求的同时，
cross platform deployment of NDN for IoT, and AR support context.
跨平台部署适用于物联网的NDN，以及支持AR上下文环境。
But also,
但同时，
trying to build on a lot of IoT work that's happened in the community before.
试图在此前社区中发生的大量物联网（IoT）工作的基础上进行拓展。
And then finally, some approaches to remote procedure calls that would
最后，一些远程过程调用的方法将会
be used to generalize the way that we invoke remote services.
被用来推广我们调用远程服务的方式。
And some demonstration of how to modify existing video codecs to take advantage
以及一些如何修改现有视频编解码器以利用
of NDNs consumer driven approach to being able to select video both in space and
NDN消费者驱动方法的优势，能够在空间和
time at the level of an individual, and the interest using names.
在个体层面上选择视频的时间，以及利用名称表达兴趣。
And of course,
当然，
we're looking at security as being built into the applications into the network.
我们正在研究将安全性内置于应用程序和网络之中。
But really, from an NDN research point of view, focusing on continuing
但实际上，从命名数据网络（NDN）研究的角度来看，重点在于持续发展。
the effort to dymatize security relationships through the use of names.
努力通过使用命名来动态化安全关系。
And so there are several examples listed on this slide that range from
因此，在这张幻灯片上列举了一些例子，这些例子涵盖了不同的范围。
new certificate schemes like Coalesce for efficient shortlived keys on IoT,
新的证书方案，例如用于物联网上高效的短暂密钥的Coalesce方案，
to continued work on our certificate infrastructure.
继续在我们的证书基础设施上进行工作。
Do some applications of attribute based cryptography that
提供了一些基于属性的加密应用，这些应用可以在我们能够在名称中指定的内容和...之间提供一个良好的桥梁，
provide a nice bridge between what we can specify in a name,
提供了一个很好的桥梁，连接了我们在名称中所能指定的内容，
in terms of the attributes that might allow verification
在可能允许验证的属性方面
of data with essentially policy in a way baked into the ABS certificates,
数据基本上在ABS证书中以一种内置政策的方式进行处理，
to access control of that context exchange that I mentioned earlier.
以及我之前提到的那种上下文交换的访问控制。
And looking also finally at availability, and
以及最后审视可用性，还有
how to handle DDoS in these circumstances.
如何在这些情况下处理DDoS攻击。
So some of the security APIs are on the call, and
有些安全API正在通话中，
I think might be interested in answering detailed questions if you'd like to
我认为如果您愿意的话，可能会对回答详细问题感兴趣。
know more about the security work, sorry.
了解更多关于安全工作的信息，抱歉。
And then the third area of research was focused on the impact of an information,
再然后，第三个研究领域集中在信息影响上，
or data centric way of thinking on the wireless layer.
或者是在无线层面上的以数据为中心的思维方式。
And if you think about NDNs intrinsic multicast behavior, it's well suited for
如果你考虑到NDN天生的多播行为，它非常适合用于
wireless media, or at least, it should be well suited for
无线媒体，或者至少，它应该很适合用于
a media that is intrinsically broadcast.
一种本质上是广播的媒体。
But the common implementations of WiFi have been focused on unicast behavior.
但是WiFi的常见实现集中在单播行为上。
So a lot of the effort in this thrust to the project was to find ways to actually
因此，该项目的很大一部分努力是为了找到实际上的方法。
take advantage and create high performance link layer wireless multicast
利用可用的NDN兴趣和数据名字，创建高性能的链路层无线组播。
that is leveraging the names that are available in NDN interest and data.
这是利用在NDN兴趣和数据中可用的名字。
And at the same time, to take further advantage of those names to start doing
并且同时，进一步利用这些名字开始进行
runtime learning and reasoning about different types of failure modes.
运行时学习和推理关于不同类型的故障模式。
So both to look at the traffic patterns based on the names themselves, but also,
因此，既要根据名称本身来观察交通模式，也要，
things that can be encoded in interest as well.
同时也要编码进兴趣中的东西。
And so some of the experimental results from the wireless group are listed below,
因此，无线组的一些实验结果如下所述，
and include higher performance multicast, improved application speeds for AR and VR.
并包括更高性能的多播、增强现实和虚拟现实应用程序速度的提升。
And decreased packet loss in these high performance multicast situations,
以及在这些高性能多播情况下减少了数据包丢失，
as well as some implementation additions to Android WiFi direct
以及对Android WiFi直连进行了一些实现上的补充。
that were important to the future of the applications that we were looking at.
这些对于我们正在研究的应用程序的未来非常重要。
And then finally, as a kinda key example of an edge service well supported by NDN.
然后最后，作为一个由NDN很好支持的边缘服务的关键例子。
We looked at FPGA based acceleration taking,
我们研究了基于FPGA的加速技术，
in this particular case, an interest in trying to ingest at the edge,
在这个特定情况下，对于尝试在边缘进行数据摄取表现出了兴趣，
low latency content from the camera that's carried on a phone or
低延迟的内容来自手机上的摄像头，或者
a headset, and go from unprocessed video.
一个耳机，以及从未经处理的视频开始。
That's something where there was some deep context about
这是某件事情，其中包含了一些深层次的背景。
what was happening with the human beings in the scene?
在那个场景中，人类发生了什么事？
So we're interested in pose recognition as an initial sort of basis for
所以我们对姿态识别感兴趣，作为一种初始的基础。
understanding activity and human behavior.
理解活动和人类行为。
>> And Jason Collins group at UCLA worked on a novel FPGA acceleration
杰森·科林斯在加州大学洛杉矶分校的小组致力于研究一种新颖的FPGA加速技术。
with low power, sort of a nice low power and high frame rate result.
这就是一个例子，展示了如何将其插入到一个低功耗且高帧率的加速器中。
That was an example of what can then be plugged into an acceleration
这就是一个可以随后插入到加速器中的例子。
as a service model, leveraging the work from Alicia Shanks group on
作为一种服务模型，利用了Alicia Shanks小组的工作成果。
this remote procedure call general mechanism.
这种远程过程调用的通用机制。
So I'm gonna use just a few minutes now at the end to talk about contributions and
所以现在我要用最后的几分钟来谈谈贡献和
lessons learned.
所学到的教训。
Maybe focusing a little bit more on the lessons.
也许应该更多地关注所学到的教训。
What we saw, we believe is a further validation of the architecture and
我们所见证的，我们相信是对架构的进一步验证，以及它在惠及这些无线边缘应用方面的方法。
its approach in benefiting these wireless edge applications.
它在惠及这些无线边缘应用方面的方法。
I wanna point out just one thing in particular,
我想特别指出一件事情。
which is the middle bullet here on the network computation and storage.
这是网络计算和存储这里的中间要点。
And I would add actually content producers and
实际上，我还要补充内容生产者和
consumers as well are all supplying the same data.
消费者们也在提供相同的数据。
And so through seamless integration into an ecosystem of new devices from
因此通过无缝集成到一个由新设备组成的生态系统中，
IoT to media and I think one place where we saw that in a very concrete and
物联网到媒体，我认为我们在一个非常具体的地方看到了这一点，而且
specific way in my are, which was focusing on applications was suddenly
在我的领域，一个特定的方式就是突然将重点放在应用程序上。
being able to look at video from several different perspectives.
能够从几个不同的角度查看视频。
Was it a bus that we could tap into a stream that we would receive in
我们能够接入的是一辆可以实时传输视频的公交车吗？
a traditional way or
传统的方式或者
essentially part of the key value store that really looked a lot like storage.
本质上是键值存储的一部分，这实际上非常类似于存储。
It actually didn't matter how the video was produced,
实际上，视频是如何制作的并不重要，
but by having it in the NDN packet format and on the network, we could use any of
但是将其放在NDN数据包格式中并置于网络上，我们可以使用任何一种
those three approaches to access both live and historical video as an example
这三种方法作为一个例子，可以访问实时和历史视频。
of the sort of impact of the architecture on how we think about applications.
这种架构对我们思考应用程序可能产生的影响。
Also, the ICR project is definitely deepened our team's understanding of
此外，ICR项目无疑加深了我们团队的理解。
the impact of the network architecture both upwards and downwards.
对网络架构向上和向下的影响。
So impacting lower layer technologies that are now optimized to support IP and
因此影响了现在为支持IP而优化的底层技术。
essentially point-to-point delivery mechanism most of the time as well as,
基本上大多数时间内都是点对点传输机制，以及，
of course, the impact on upper layer apps in terms of how they think
当然，这对上层应用在它们的思考方式上的影响。
about moving content around,
关于移动内容，
making connections before they proceed with exchanging content and so on.
在他们进行内容交换等操作之前建立联系。
Certainly there's impact in the middle and on the approach to security, as well.
当然，这也会对中间层以及安全性方法论产生影响。
We saw I think from that impact on the upper and lower layers, some challenges
我们认为，从那种对上层和下层的影响中，我们看到了一些挑战。
that we hadn't really expected on quantitative comparisons implementation.
我们确实没有预料到，在定量比较的实施上，会有一些我们没想到的好的性能结果。
So certainly there are some nice performance results from the subareas that
所以毫无疑问，从各个子领域中我们确实获得了一些不错的性能结果。
I mentioned briefly in the previous slides, but
我在之前的幻灯片中简要提到过，但是
a lot of those took far more implementation effort than we'd expected
很多工作的实施努力超出了我们的预期。
to access lower layers in the protocol stack or to modify the media formats and
访问协议堆栈中的较低层或修改媒体格式和
protocols that are intertwined and increasingly complex ways.
协议以交织且日益复杂的方式运作。
Bacon assumptions and certainly to start testing things in larger AR platforms and
贝肯的假设无疑是开始在更大的AR平台上测试事物的起点。
game engines that are in, and
游戏引擎本身就是重要的软件工程项目。
of themselves significant software engineering projects.
本身就是重要的软件工程项目。
So there was a lot, I think that we learned about how to potentially
所以我认为我们学到了很多关于如何可能
support this kind of experimentation a little better in the future and
支持这种实验在未来更好的进行。
maybe lobby a bit for more access to the hardware and
也许可以适当游说以获取更多的硬件访问权限，
operating system functionality that's needed to really demo NDN's value.
操作系统功能，这是真正展示NDN价值所必需的。
So one of the common questions we got was well,
那么我们常见的一个问题是，嗯，
can't we use the same thing using IP?
我们不能用IP做同样的事情吗？
And there are a few answers here.
这里有一些答案。
I won't go into all of them, but this is a nice conversation that we might be able to
我不会详述所有内容，但这是一个不错的对话，我们可能有机会
have in some of the panels over the course of the next several days.
在接下来的几天里，我们将在一些小组讨论中有所涉猎。
But then to wrap up here with a little bit more on our sort of understanding
但在此最后总结一下，关于我们对这方面理解的更多内容。
is we were really looking for OS platforms to allow deeper access to the network.
我们真正寻求的是允许更深入访问网络的操作系统平台。
And so that's a place that we need to maybe provide some support for
因此，那是我们可能需要提供一些支持的地方。
researchers.
研究人员。
Certainly we wanted to try to allow applications to implement a data centric
当然，我们希望尝试允许应用程序实现以数据为中心的
paradigm directly in the application design,
范式直接集成到应用程序设计中，
which was something that the Indian CNL library tries to do.
这是印度CNL图书馔尝试去做的事情。
And in cases where we can with that type of library to allow
以及在我们可以使用那种类型的图书馆来允许
that data centric designed to also operate at the network level and
那种以数据为中心的设计也旨在在网络层面上运作，并且
provides something where there's not maybe as much of a semantic gap between how
提供了一种东西，在这里可能语义上的差距没有那么大，介于应用设计师的工作方式和NDN网络的运作方式之间。
application designers are working, and how the NDN network works.
应用设计师的工作方式，以及NDN网络的运作方式。
And this is guiding us towards, hopefully some future fruitful areas of focus.
这正引导我们朝着希望能够成为未来富有成效的关注领域前进。
We're not trying to change everything all at once, but
我们不是试图一次性改变所有事情，而是
work potentially bit by bit from the edge focusing on plug and play behavior.
逐步从边缘开始，专注于即插即用的行为。
the NDN platform and greenfields where a lot of this previous sort of
NDN平台和绿地，在这些地方之前的许多类似的事情
the previous emphasis and optimizations for IPR had less of a foothold.
之前对知识产权的重视和优化措施并没有太大的立足点。
So some of the the future work is listed here and happy to talk about any of that.
所以一些未来的工作在这里列出了，我很乐意讨论其中的任何内容。
>> Yeah, maybe I'll take one question if there is one.
如果有人提问的话，我可以回答一个问题。
If not, then maybe a final comment on the most exciting future work as you see it.
如果没有问题的话，那么或许可以就您认为最激动人心的未来工作做一个最后的评论。
Is there a question out there?
有没有什么问题？
Thank you for a great presentation.
谢谢你精彩的演讲。
Okay, final thoughts on exciting future.
好的，关于激动人心的未来的最后想法。
>> I can tell you the final thought that's sort of the most exciting for
我可以告诉你最令人兴奋的最后一个想法是什么
me which is plug and play sounds simple or maybe simplistic, but
我认为“即插即用”听起来很简单，甚至可能过于简化，但是
I think the more that we can take this experience in the last three years and
我认为我们越是能够借鉴过去三年的经验，
at each within each thrust look at ways to get these tools into the hands of as
在每一次推进中，寻找方法将这些工具交到尽可能多的研究人员和实验者手中。
many researchers and experimenters as possible.
将这些工具交到尽可能多的研究人员和实验者手中。
That seems to be one of the most exciting parts of the future work right now.
这似乎是当前未来工作中最激动人心的部分之一。
>> And with that, you're focusing on the ease of configurability, I think.
>> 正因为此，我认为你专注于配置的便利性。
>> Ease of configurability, but I think also trying to find ways to have
>> 便于配置，但我认为也在努力寻找方法来实现
the API's present an easy to understand data centric perspective.
API提供了一个易于理解的以数据为中心的视角。
So it's definitely making things work as simply as possible to experiment,
所以它确实在尽可能简化事物，以便于进行实验，
but also trying to kind of help guide applications to a data centric perspective
但同时也试图以某种方式引导应用程序转向以数据为中心的视角。
that allows them to take advantage of the network behavior underneath.
这使他们能够利用底层的网络行为。
>> Great, can the organisers tell us,
>> 太好了，组织者能告诉我们吗？
do we have time for one more question?
我们还有时间再问一个问题吗？
>> Don't think so leave.
>> 我认为不要这么想就离开。
>> Okay, we'll take it offline.
>> 好的，我们私下里讨论。
>> Thank you so much.
>> 非常感谢您。
>> Thank you all.
>> 谢谢大家。
>> Thank you very much.
>> 非常感谢。
The agenda has the next panel two, but
议程上接下来是第二个小组讨论，但是
we have Ilya who missed the big recession and
我们有伊利亚，他错过了那次大衰退，而且
So we're delaying panel two no more than ten minutes, Ilya.
所以我们将延迟第二个小组讨论不超过十分钟，伊利亚。
>> Okay, great.
>> 好的，太好了。
So yes, thank you for having me here today.
所以是的，感谢今天有我在此。
I think my presentation be somewhat out of maybe not quite in context with everything
我认为我的演讲可能有些脱离了上下文。
else that was discussed, because it's not specific to Indian architecture.
因为它并不特定于印度建筑，所以可能与讨论的其他内容不太相关。
So fabric is a midscale research infrastructure.
所以织物是一种中等规模的研究基础设施。
Project funded last year before years to build a nationwide
去年资助的项目旨在建立一个全国性的
networking testbed that will allow experimentation with
网络测试平台，它将允许进行实验，涉及到
a variety of distributed, verticals, applications and
各种分布式的、垂直的、应用程序和
architectures with a key idea being that it is really kind of
架构的一个关键思想是它确实有点
time to look at potentially putting more state in the network.
考虑在网络中增加更多状态的时机已经到来。
And what form that state might take we as the builders of this
我们作为这一基础设施的构建者，应该考虑这种状态可能呈现的形式。
infrastructure try not to have too much influence on,
基础设施尽量不要对此产生太多影响，
rather just trying to create as many options there for experimenters to try.
而只是尽量为实验者创造更多的尝试选项。
And of course, NDN architecture is one example of an open new
当然，NDN架构就是一个开放的新例子。
internet architecture that has more state that requires storage and
互联网架构需要存储更多状态信息，
processing capabilities out of the network.
需要将处理能力从网络中分离出来。
But as I said, we ourselves as the builders of this infrastructure,
但正如我所说，作为这一基础设施的建设者，
try to remain neutral to the various possibilities.
努力对各种可能性保持中立。
That should the computing community has a chance to explore
计算机界应有机会去探索
these various inflection points in the architecture and
这些架构中的各种拐点和
then decide what works and what doesn't at a reasonable level of scale.
然后决定在合理的规模水平上什么有效，什么无效。
So, just to briefly introduce the leadership team has myself and
所以，简单介绍一下领导团队，包括我自己和
Nita Nicolaj from inner cylinder Urbana Champaign in the manga is the executive
内塔·尼科莱来自内圆筒城市厄巴纳-香槟，在漫画中是执行者。
director of Department of Energy's energy sciences network.
能源部能源科学网络的主任。
Jim Griffin from University of Kentucky, Casey Wang from Clemson.
吉姆·格里芬来自肯塔基大学，凯西·王来自克莱姆森大学。
Tom layman, also Polo Roof and Zong Ling, Fei.
汤姆·莱曼，还有波罗·鲁夫和宗凌，飞。
So what is fabric?
那么什么是fabric呢？
As I mentioned, its goal to enable a new paradigm for
正如我所提到的，它的目标是为了启用一个新的范式来
distributed protocols, applications and architectures.
分布式协议、应用程序和架构。
The intent is to build a nationwide programmable network
旨在构建一个全国范围的可编程网络。
with significant compute storage capabilities at each node within the core,
拥有在核心每个节点内的显著计算存储能力，
not just at the edge, but in the core.
不仅在边缘，还在核心。
Such that you have a continuum now of possibilities of where to put your storage
因此，你现在有了一个连续的可能性范围，用于决定在哪里放置你的存储。
computation on data as it travels through the network.
计算可以在数据通过网络传输时进行。
And the idea is that the computation can be supported by a variety of augmented
计算可以得到各种增强设备的支持。
computing devices like GPU like FPGAs, network processors, etc etc.
计算设备，如GPU、FPGA、网络处理器等等。
Quality of Service is important from repeatability, reproducibility of
服务质量从可重复性、可复制性的角度来看是很重要的。
experience point of view, we shouldn't forget that this is a testbed, so
从经验的角度来看，我们不应该忘记这是一个试验平台，所以
that's provided by dedicated hundred gigabit optical links.
这是由专用的百吉比特光纤链路提供的。
And then also the ideas of fabric is not in itself a sandbox, but
而且所谓的网络结构并不是一个独立的沙盒环境，而是
rather in connects incentives to interconnect other facilities HPC
而是将激励措施与连接其他设施的高性能计算(HPC)联系起来。
centers cloud wireless test bits Public clouds, commercial clouds and
公共云、商业云以及
a number of edge nodes such that the experimenter can pick what her
实验者可以选择所需的边缘节点数量，以便让她的
kind of selection of resources is within her global experiment and
实验者可以在其全球实验中选择所需的资源种类，以及
you know, pick the ones that are closest to what what she needs.
你知道的，选择那些最接近她所需的资源。
Rather than having to kind of reinvent everything from scratch because fabric
因为面料的原因，我们没有必要从头开始重新发明一切。
really can't and shouldn't try to reproduce the entirety of the ecosystem of
真的不能也不应该试图复制整个生态系统的完整性。
computation on other resources available to researchers today.
而是在今天研究人员可用的其他资源上进行计算。
Instead it's producing.
它反而在生产。
It provides a separate way of transporting data between those
它提供了一种在它们之间传输数据的独立方式。
while computing on it in flight, essentially.
在飞行过程中进行计算，基本上就是这样。
This is our idea of what the topology will look like when it's completed.
这是我们对于拓扑结构完成时的样子的想法。
Of course, subject to change over the next few years.
当然，这在接下来的几年中可能会有所改变。
We're at the end of year one of the four year construction project.
我们已经完成了四年建设项目的第一年。
All the blue links are dedicated hundred gig capacity.
所有蓝色链接都是专用的百吉比特容量。
And then the yellow is what we call this terabit super core.
然后黄色的部分是我们所说的太比特超级核心。
This is where we plan to have some version of a terabit network
这是我们计划建设某种形式的太比特网络的地方。
either it's one terabit 1.2 terabit per second.
无论是一太比特还是每秒1.2太比特。
Of course, there are locations where we will appear with public clouds using
当然，我们会在某些地方出现，使用公共云进行连接。
internet to Cloud Connect system.
互联网到云连接系统。
Such that, you can't really think of an experiment and
因此，你真的无法想象一个实验并
infrastructure today that doesn't include some version of a public cloud.
如今的基础设施都会包含某种形式的公共云服务。
So obviously that's that's a requirement and
所以很明显，这是一个需求。
then you can see also all the facilities, at least the initial list of facilities,
然后你也可以看到所有的设施，至少是最初的设施列表，
we're going to connect Do you see tag cloud love powder cosmos,
我们将要连接，你看到了标签云，爱情粉末，宇宙，
the Pittsburgh supercomputing center mgh, PCC, etc, etc.
匹兹堡超级计算中心，MGH，PCC等等。
A little bit about the hardware.
关于硬件方面的一点介绍。
So the whole idea is that we want to interpose compute and
所以整个想法是我们想要在计算之间进行插入和
storage, different types of compute and
存储、不同类型的计算和
storage into the path of fast packet flows that are right in the network.
存储进入网络中快速数据包流动的路径。
So, you know, each site is a rack of high performance servers,
因此，你知道，每个站点都是一组高性能服务器，
dual dual CPU 32 core, have half a terabyte
双双CPU 32核心，拥有半个TB的RAM，在每个站点的服务器中有不同类型。
of RAM, different flavors of servers in each site.
的RAM，在每个站点的服务器中有不同类型。
Some have loaded with GPUs, some of FPGAs and network cards.
有些服务器装载了GPU，有些则装有FPGA和网卡。
Storage of different tiers on
不同层次的存储设备上
some experimental provisional NVMe drives as well as rotating storage at each site.
一些实验性的临时NVMe驱动器以及每个站点的旋转存储设备。
And of course, everything connecting with to a to a to a switch that has
当然，一切都连接到一个交换机上，该交换机具有
different types of Port speeds from 25 to 100 and above.
不同类型的端口速度从25到100甚至更高。
Gigabits per second.
千兆比特每秒。
FPGAs with support for P4, as is another goal and then mellanox Connect X-5 and
支持P4的FPGA，这是另一个目标，然后是Mellanox ConnectX-5。
6 family cards as kind of hardware offload cards with OBS and things like that.
6系列卡作为具有OBS等功能的硬件卸载卡。
And then the idea is that the experimenter essentially gets access to these devices.
然后，这个想法是实验者基本上能够访问这些设备。
Primarily the mode we envision is using virtual machines with direct
我们主要设想的模式是使用具有直接连接的虚拟机。
attached PCI devices for some high value experiments, we can see
将PCI设备直接连接到一些高价值实验的虚拟机中，我们可以看到
dedicating entire servers to those and provisioning them for that experiment.
将整台服务器专门用于那些实验，并为那个实验配置它们。
However, given the kind of the size of the facility,
然而，考虑到设施的大小，
the amount of resources at each site,
我们认为为了使这成为一种成功的多用户设施，我们拥有的每个地点的资源数量，
we think that In order to make this a kind of successful multi user facility, we have
我们认为为了使这成为一种成功的多用户设施，我们拥有的
to rely on some level of virtualization to achieve a level of scale.
需要依赖某种程度的虚拟化来实现规模化。
A typical experiment in fabric, this is absolutely unrealistic but
一个典型的在织物中进行的实验，这完全是不现实的，但
it just sort of shows some of the ideas as purposely Showing on top of a map of
它只是在某种程度上展示了一些故意在地图上方展示的想法，
the United States just to show the level of this distributed capacity or,
美国只是为了展示这种分布式能力的水平，或者说，
you might connect some external resource like, a cluster attack or SDSC, for
您可能会连接一些外部资源，比如集群攻击或者SDSC，以便
instance, and then maybe you're sampling traffic that's going through this link.
实例中，然后可能你正在抽样分析通过这个链接的流量。
And you're using an SSD like an NVMe drive and
你正在使用像NVMe驱动器这样的固态硬盘。
an FPGA to do some additional processing on the data and
它通常是像光纤或者电缆上的一个提升。
it's usually it's it's like a bump in fiber or bump on wire.
它通常就像是光纤或电线上的一个凸起。
Then maybe you want to build a virtual switch out of these different
那么也许你想要用这些不同的组件来构建一个虚拟交换机。
network cards, some of them perhaps.
网络卡，也许有些是这样的。
With the four capabilities, some of them just kind of OBS, or
有了这四种能力，其中一些可能只是类似OBS的东西，或者
maybe you're hosting an application within the network that uses GPUs, and again,
也许你在网络中托管了一个应用程序，它使用了GPU，同样地，
maybe fast drives for caching data, things like that.
也许是用于缓存数据的快速驱动器之类的东西。
And we also have room for a small number of dedicated p for
我们还有空间用于少量专用的 p 用于
switches if you really want very, very high port counts for density.
如果你真的需要非常非常高的端口数量来提高密度，那么可以使用交换机。
Comparatively high port density in a few locations, you could also do that.
在少数几个位置你也可以实现相对较高的端口密度。
Yeah, this was kind of a conceptual idea of what a fabric now it looks like.
是的，这是对现在所谓网络结构外观的一种概念性想法。
There's a head node or
这里有一个头节点或者说主节点。
something that will workers equipped with different flavours of these PCI devices.
用于装备有这些不同类型PCI设备的工作节点。
two switches management switch for external access one data plane switch for
两台交换机，一台管理交换机用于外部访问，一台数据平面交换机用于
accessing the actual topology that you create As an experimenter,
访问您作为实验者创建的实际拓扑。
just some of the examples of the use cases that that
这只是一些使用案例的例子，这些案例就是
might be useful particularly to this community, right?
可能特别对这个社区有用，对吧？
So with NDN wanting to do storage and processing of data in the network.
所以，NDN希望在网络中进行数据的存储和处理。
This is kind of part and parcel here of the architecture for
这是架构的一部分，也是其本质所在。
fabric You can do sort of direct pass through just the switch.
如果你想直接穿过交换机，你可以进行直接通行。
If you just want to bypass the site, you can pop the traffic into the site and
如果你只是想绕过站点，你可以将流量直接引入站点内并
do some processing within the site storage or processing on the fly.
在站点存储中进行一些处理或即时处理。
You can host the entire application and again have avid serve.
您可以托管整个应用程序，并再次让Avid服务器提供服务。
Packet flows coming in from multiple points.
数据包从多个点进入流动。
So line rate stateful.
因此是线速状态保持的。
And again, we don't know dictate what the state represents so within this case.
而且，我们并不确定状态代表了什么，所以在这种情况下。
It could be the data caches, it could be some control plane state,
它可能是数据缓存，也可能是某些控制平面状态，
some combination of the two.
可能是这两者的某种组合。
That's up to the experimenter to decide.
这取决于实验者来决定。
We're also paying a lot of attention to measurement capabilities.
我们也非常关注测量能力。
So, each site likely was going to have a just GPS discipline clock for PTP.
所以，每个站点可能都会有一个仅用于PTP的GPS授时钟。
But so that you can take kind of
但这样你就可以进行某种
Packet Tracer spec of snapshots across the network with millisecond accuracy.
Packet Tracer 可以以毫秒级精度捕获网络中的快照。
And have some idea of what's going through the network.
并且能够了解网络中正在传输的内容。
Now obviously, it's very high packet rates like hundred gigabits per second,
显然，这是非常高的数据包传输率，比如每秒一百千兆比特，
you won't be able to hold a whole lot of traffic in these.
这些设备无法处理太多的流量。
But nonetheless, it's a possibility that it opens up to do this.
但尽管如此，这确实为我们提供了这样做的可能性。
We will have smart videos as well as the server's themselves instrumented for
我们将会对智能视频以及服务器本身进行仪器化处理，用于
measuring power consumption.
监测功耗。
Some optical layer measurements were available, now this facility will not have
一些光层测量数据曾是可用的，现在这个设施将不会拥有这些数据。
an edge optical layer, that's not part of the architecture.
边缘光层，并不是架构的一部分。
However, some level of measurements from the optical layer should be available.
然而，应该能够获取来自光层的一些级别的测量数据。
And of course, the traditional utilization measures from CPU, memory,
当然，还有来自CPU、内存的传统利用率测量指标。
disk etc, for their accounts.
磁盘等资源的使用情况也将被纳入他们的账户。
Port mirroring will be supported as well, so
端口镜像也将得到支持，所以
that you can capture certain flows if you want.
你可以捕获特定的流量，如果你想的话。
And I think that's it.
我认为就是这样。
I wanted to keep it short and perhaps leave a little bit of room for
我想保持简短，或许留一些空间给
questions instead.
问题。
I'm gonna stop sharing maybe for now and wait for questions.
我现在可能会停止分享，等待问题。
There's a question of how users conduct experiments, can you hear me?
有一个关于用户如何进行实验的问题，你能听见我吗？
Can you hear me okay?
你能听清楚我说的吗？
>> Yes, we heard you.
是的，我们听到你说的了。
>> Yeah, so, the users define the topology of what they want to do,
是的，所以用户定义了他们想要做的拓扑结构，
they define the properties of that topology,
他们定义了那个拓扑结构的属性。
they define the elements of the topology in the configuration.
他们在配置中定义了拓扑结构的元素。
Essentially, it's either going through the portal or using the API's.
本质上，它要么通过门户进行操作，要么使用API。
The user interface is going to,
用户界面将要，
a primary user interface is likely to be through Jupiter notebooks.
一个主要的用户界面很可能是通过Jupyter笔记本来实现的。
So that you have a programmable kind of scriptable environment where you can
因此你会有一个可编程的、可脚本化的环境，在这里你可以
launch your experiments, configure it, collect data,
启动你的实验，配置它，收集数据，
process data and then hopefully get the results you're looking for the.
处理数据，然后希望得到你期望的结果。
So this gonna rely on federated identity.
所以这将依赖于联合身份认证。
So the researchers from the US institutions are part of in common
所以来自美国机构的研究人员是in common的一部分。
federation should have no trouble accessing this.
联邦应该可以轻松访问这个。
By the time we're done with the construction, we will have an AUP, as well
到我们完成建设的时候，我们也会有一个接受使用政策（AUP）。
as other policies to help understand how best to use facility in the near future.
在不久的将来，我们还会制定其他政策来帮助理解如何最好地使用设施。
And we're planning to open up a facility to early experimenters in the summer of
我们计划在夏季向早期实验者开放一个设施。
2021.
2021年。
It's going to be more of a kind of a first come first serve.
这将会是一种先到先得的模式。
We will be working with some members of the research community to kinda help us
我们将与研究界的一些成员合作，以便为我们提供帮助。
come in and kick the tires on the facility,
进来试试这个设施的性能。
figure out what works, what doesn't, what can work better.
找出什么有效，什么无效，什么可以做得更好。
So the answer is no, this is a construction project,
所以答案是否定的，这是一个建筑项目，
we've only completed the first year as I just mentioned,
我们刚刚完成了第一年，正如我刚才提到的，
the general availability is 2023, limited availability is next year 2021.
总体上市时间是2023年，有限上市时间是明年2021年。
So how we can calculate participate in the fabric?
所以我们如何才能计算参与这个项目？
So the first thing I would encourage you to do is to visit our website.
所以我首先建议您做的事情是访问我们的网站。
What is fabric.net?
fabric.net是什么？在那里有一个按钮，你可以点击“参与进来”。
What is fabric.net, there is a button there, you can click get involved and
fabric.net是什么，在那里有一个按钮，你可以点击“参与进来”并且
you will get monthly or periodic anyways mailers as to what's going on.
你会定期收到邮件，了解正在发生的事情。
We are hosting a number of workshops with different members of different
我们正在举办多个研讨会，与不同社区的不同成员合作，
communities, trying to collect more requirements, ideas for experiments,
社区，试图收集更多的需求、实验的想法，
tools that could be useful to other experimenters.
可能对其他实验者有用的工具。
One of the things that we have in mind is being able to stand up kind of an on
我们考虑的一个方面是能够建立一种即开即用的
demand NDN profile experiment within fabric such that.
需要在fabric中进行NDN配置实验。
People who want to use NDN kind of out of the box can just kind of press the button
想要直接使用NDN的人可以简单地按下按钮。
and launch in NDN network of the size that they want across the country.
并且可以在他们想要的全国范围内启动所需规模的NDN网络。
So that idea of an experiment profile is pretty integral to our thinking.
因此，实验配置文件的概念对我们的思考至关重要。
Yes, the idea of fabric is that you have dedicated resources.
是的，fabric的理念就是你拥有专用资源。
The question was, would the experimenters have dedicated resources if necessary?
实验人员如有必要，会有专用资源吗？
Yes, the whole idea is that you reserve the resources that you need, and
是的，整个想法就是你预留你需要的资源，然后
we either tell you sorry we're not available help you with a calendar.
我们要么告诉你很抱歉我们没有空帮你管理日程安排。
Schedule your experiment in the future or
安排你未来的实验或者
provide your resources right away if they're available.
如果资源现成可用的话，请立即提供你的资源。
But reproducibility which, reproducibility is the driver here,
但为了获得可重复性，可重复性才是这里的驱动力，
but in order to get the reproducibility, you have to have dedicated resources.
但为了获得可重复性，你必须拥有专用的资源。
Usually reserved for your use.
通常为您保留以供使用。
Fabric will also offer a shared layer three capacity for
Fabric还将为层三提供共享的容量。
those types of experiments where perhaps current IP
这些实验类型也许是目前的IP
implementation is enough to move the data around.
实现起来足以移动数据。
But the experimenter might be just interested
但实验者可能只是感兴趣
in experimenting with higher level concepts and applications and
在实验更高层次的概念和应用时，
they don't really want to rule the whole entire architecture or protocol stack.
他们并不真的想要掌控整个架构或协议栈。
Or they just wanna experiment with applications, but in addition to that,
或者他们只是想要尝试一些应用程序，但除此之外，
to that layer three default kind of best effort layer three,
将会有专门的容量可以在整个网络中预留。
there will be dedicated capacity that will be reservable across the entire footprint.
We also have an extension now, plans extension to Europe and Japan.
我们现在还扩展了业务，计划将业务扩展到欧洲和日本。
So United Kingdom, Bristol,
所以英国，布里斯托尔，
the Netherlands Interserve Amsterdam, Switzerland CERN,
荷兰Interserve阿姆斯特丹，瑞士欧洲核子研究中心（CERN），
Interserve Tokyo, we will have sites there as well.
Interserve东京，我们也将在那里设立站点。
>> Okay, I guess we're getting ready for the IoT and edge applications panel.
好的，我想我们正在为物联网和边缘应用小组讨论做准备。
Maybe all the panelists can start to get ready.
也许所有的小组成员可以开始准备了。
And I wanted to kind of start out just saying,
我想先从说开始。
what distinguishes edge applications.
区分边缘应用程序的特点是什么。
And it's nice that we had this earlier session where
我们很高兴我们之前有一个会议环节在哪里。
we had people speaking about different edge applications.
我们有人谈论了不同的边缘计算应用。
And we had that morning session, which was sort of the opposite and
我们还举行了早间会议，内容则与之相反，
those applications made heavy use of caching and storage and
这些应用程序大量使用了缓存和存储功能，以及
movement of persistent data.
持久数据的移动。
And I think that in contrast to Ed's application is kind
与艾德的应用相比，我认为这种做法是出于善意的。
of focus on using NDN as a communication protocol and
关注使用NDN作为通信协议。
the data could be more affirmable although still maybe durable.
数据虽然可能更耐用，但也会更加确凿。
And it makes really heavy use of security so that in the automotive applications and
它确实大量使用了安全措施，以便在汽车应用中能够
really exploit that broadcast nature of the edge networks.
充分利用边缘网络的广播特性。
And that was something that Jeff mentioned in his talk.
杰夫在他的演讲中提到了这一点。
And I think it was particularly interesting how the Intel
我认为英特尔公司如何做到这一点特别有趣。
person kind of set this up for us.
人们为我们安排好了这一切。
And I think that NDN as a NSF project really did get
而我认为NDN作为一个NSF项目确实得到了
started not looking at the edge because it was a future internet application.
开始之时并未关注边缘，因为它是一个未来的互联网应用。
But it's interesting to note that the roots of this and
但有趣的是，这一切的根源是
the new way to look at networking and some of the early work at
新的网络观点以及一些早期的工作在
PARC really was focused on things you could do with the edge.
PARC 真的很专注于你可以在边缘做的事情。
And when you do that, you don't have to worry so much about IP routing and
当你那样做的时候，你就不需要太担心IP路由和
other elements of the infrastructure that we already have, and
你可以在边缘用NDN风格的通信解决那个问题。
you can solve that problem at the edge with NDN style communications.
So what we're gonna do here is I'm going to have these
所以我们要做的是我将要让这些
four excellent panelists speak too.
四位出色的小组成员也将发言。
We'll do it in the order of Justin Caswell,
接着是Justin Caswell，
then Dan Massey, then and then Dang Hu.
然后是Dan Massey，接着是Dang Hu。
And I wanna start with Justin.
我想从Justin开始。
And what, I wanted to introduce Justin,
我本来想介绍Justin，
but I lost that, my introduction.
但我把那个介绍弄丢了。
I hope they get it.
我希望他们能明白。
Okay, I do not have it anymore.
好吧，我已经没有了。
Okay, well hang on a second.
好的，稍等一下。
[LAUGH] All right, so Justin is the founder and CEO of Rakhine,
好的，所以贾斯汀是Rakhine的创始人和首席执行官，
which is a company that focuses on blockchain network solutions for
是一家专注于区块链网络解决方案的公司，用于
the telecommunications industry.
他在电信行业拥有20多年的经验，主要专注于无线通信系统。
He's had 20 plus years and communication systems with a focus on wireless for
both terrestrial and satellite.
包括陆地和卫星通信。
And that includes companies like ExxonMobil and FedEx.
这包括了像埃克森美孚和联邦快递这样的公司。
Justin is a serial entrepreneur, a full stack developer and an innovative leader.
贾斯汀是一个连续创业者，全栈开发者和创新领导者。
He works directly with network operators, data centers, governments and
他直接与网络运营商、数据中心、政府以及
private industry in cutting edge technology operations.
他的工作特别聚焦于5G网络领域，涉及到尖端技术运营的私营产业。
His work has a specific focus within 5G networks,
他的工作特别聚焦于5G网络领域，
advanced communication systems, leveraging AI and of course, NDN.
高级通信系统，利用人工智能以及当然还有NDN（命名数据网络）。
So, Justin, do you wanna go ahead and
那么，贾斯汀，你想不想继续并且……
explain to us some of the issues that you see and
向我们解释一些你所看到的问题以及……
things that will be interesting to the audience?
向我们解释一些你所看到的问题以及会引起观众兴趣的事情。谢谢。
Thanks.
谢谢。
>> Thanks, Kathy for the introduction, yeah, so
谢谢你的介绍，Kathy，是的，所以
some of the things we're working on.
我们正在努力的一些事情。
So just right out of the gate, I think what our involvement was with NDN is we
我们一开始参与NDN的工作，我认为我们的参与是
wanted to use a blockchain application running on top of NDN.
想要在NDN之上运行一个区块链应用程序。
Because there's [LAUGH] a lot of efficiencies you can you can
因为有很多效率你可以获得。
glean from just that.
你可以从中学到的东西。
But then we we moved into a little bit more of the core network operations and
但后来我们进一步深入到了核心网络运营领域。
we started looking at saying, okay, well, how can we apply NDN in a 5G deployment or
我们开始考虑，好的，我们如何在5G部署中应用NDN呢，或者
any kind of modern wireless network deployment really?
任何一种现代无线网络部署，不是吗？
So we kind of started dialing in on the IoT aspects,
所以我们开始专注于物联网方面的事宜，
the challenges wrapped around encryption, bringing that in through your gateway.
围绕加密的挑战，通过您的网关实现这一点。
Lots of proprietary gateways and
许多专有网关和
hardware out there that you have to overcome, so a lot of challenges there.
要克服的硬件问题很多，所以存在许多挑战。
I think if we can work a little bit more with OEMs and get NDN integrated
我认为如果我们能与原始设备制造商（OEM）多合作一些，将NDN集成进去，
directly into devices, I think that would be a substantial step forward.
直接集成到设备中，我认为这将是一个重大的进步。
In addition to that, I think if we could get NDN,
除此之外，我认为如果我们能够得到NDN，
working directly in the gateways for those devices.
直接在这些设备的网关中工作。
That's another substantial challenge,
这是另一个重大的挑战，
that I think that would bring a lot to the industry.
我认为这将为行业带来很多好处。
Some of the other things that we started looking at moving away from just IoT, but
我们开始关注的其他事项之一，就是从仅仅关注物联网(IoT)转向其他领域，但是
really looking at broad compute platforms, right?
我们真的在广泛考察计算平台，对吧？
So how do you take all of these things at the edge, whether that's IoT devices or
那么，你是如何处理所有这些边缘设备的，无论是物联网设备还是
you're taking autonomous vehicles, or UAV's or Smart Cities.
你正在处理的是无人驾驶汽车、无人航空器或智能城市。
So there's a ton of data that you need to ingest, especially,
所以有大量的数据需要你去摄取，尤其是，
whenever you start looking at 5G deployments.
当你开始关注5G部署时。
So whenever you say, all right, we've got all these devices.
所以当你说，好的，我们有了这么多设备。
We've got all these users just machine to machine,
我们有所有这些用户，只是机器对机器，
some of its actual users to users.
有些是真正的用户对用户。
And you've got all these different dynamic sets of information that you're
而你拥有所有这些不同的动态信息集合。
pulling in.
正在吸收中。
Now, you're not only having to deal with the baseband processing of that, right?
现在，你不仅要处理基带处理，对吧？
But now,
但现在，
you have to take these these applications that are running on that 5G network.
你必须要处理那些运行在5G网络上的应用程序。
And then now, you have to say, okay, well, how are we gonna get it pushed through and
然后现在，你得说好，我们将如何推动它的实施呢？
actually meet the requirements of the low latency that 5G kind of requires?
实际上满足了5G所要求的低延迟需求吗？
So looking at that, we were working on an edge based solution.
所以看这个情况，我们正在研究一个基于边缘计算的解决方案。
It's a mobile edge compute platform that integrates NDN in the middle of
它是一个移动边缘计算平台，在中间集成了NDN。
the technology stack.
技术栈。
So we're using Mellanox NIC's programmable NIC's kind of under the network side.
所以我们在网络方面使用了Mellanox的可编程网卡。
So we're just layering that in, and
所以我们就在那个基础上逐层增加，然后
then we're using sub-frameworks to build out some intelligent routing platforms.
然后我们使用子框架来构建一些智能路由平台。
And we're just leveraging some AI and some other existing frameworks that are out
我们还在利用一些人工智能以及其他一些现有的框架。
there currently, but we're going to be expanding on those.
我们目前在那里已有一些基础，但我们将会在这些基础上进行扩展。
And so what we'll actually do is combine the baseband processing.
所以我们实际上要做的是结合基带处理。
We put NDN in the middle, right, and
我们将NDN放在中间，对，然后
then we can push the the next the Mellanox NIC's down below.
然后我们可以将下一个Mellanox网卡推到下面。
And what that's allowing us to do theoretically, we haven't proven this yet,
而这在理论上允许我们做的是，我们还没有证明这一点，
but what we're hoping to prove right, is that now we can intelligently move
但我们希望能证明的是，现在我们可以智能地移动
data across the RAND, or from edge or local data centers.
跨RAND或从边缘或本地数据中心传输数据。
Back out to these edge compute platforms and so
我们将数据回传到这些边缘计算平台，因此
we're looking at an efficiency level for for routing.
我们正在考察用于路由的效率水平。
But what we're also really considering here is having a data aware
但我们在这里真正考虑的还有拥有数据感知能力。
platform where now, you can deploy these these edge based applications.
平台上，现在你可以部署这些基于边缘的应用程序。
Would typically normally run at like a public cloud level.
通常会在公共云层级上运行。
And so now, if you can push that out onto this mobile edge compute platform that can
然后将其推送到这个可以支持移动边缘计算的平台上，
then be tied into a 5G wireless network.
然后将其与5G无线网络相连。
It doesn't have to be a 5G wireless network, but obviously,
它不一定要是5G无线网络，但显然，
you get a lot of benefits if you if it's tied in there.
如果它与那里相连，你会得到很多好处。
And so the idea right is that now you can have operators running their
所以这个想法是，现在你可以让操作员在这个计算平台上运行他们的
applications on this compute platform.
你可以让开发者在这个计算平台上运行应用程序。
You can have developers running application on this compute platform.
But you're also really getting a lot of network efficiencies on both
但你也确实在两边都获得了很多网络效率上的提升。
the RAND side, and then your hardline network side.
在RAND方面，然后是你的硬线网络方面。
And so those are kind of the main things that we're looking at,
所以这些是我们主要关注的几个方面。
we've got a lot of interest on on those.
我们对这些领域有很大的兴趣。
We're doing some test beds here in the United States, down in Texas, and
我们在美国这边做了一些测试平台，在德克萨斯州下面，还有
then also in a couple of other countries,
然后还在其他几个国家，
where they're interested in this type of a solution.
他们对这类解决方案感兴趣的地方。
That being said, we're also launching some of our own applications on that mobile
也就是说，我们还在那个移动平台上推出了一些自己的应用程序。
edge compute platform.
边缘计算平台。
And so that's tying it to more of like a gaming use case,
因此，这更多地将其与游戏用例联系起来。
just working with kind of NVIDIA and some others in that room.
所以我们正在与NVIDIA以及该领域的其他一些公司合作。
So we've got some pretty substantial challenges on our side.
所以我们这边面临着一些相当大的挑战。
Everything is pretty new right now, we're still figuring out a lot of the the 5G
现在一切都相当新颖，我们还在摸索很多关于5G的事情。
infrastructure build out and deployments.
基础设施建设和部署。
Especially, whenever you look,
尤其是，无论你何时看。
just at the global kind of 5G evolution that's going on.
正处于全球正在进行的5G发展之中。
But we believe that where the real unlocking potential is at the edge.
但我们认为真正的解锁潜力在于边缘计算。
We feel the networks will come up to par, right,
我们认为网络性能将会达到标准。
through the evolution of 5G on the wireless side.
通过无线端5G的演进。
And then the data centers,
而数据中心，
and the networks themselves there, we also feel are gonna be upgraded as
和那里的网络本身，我们也认为将会得到升级，
well over the coming years to meet those demands of the 5G.
在未来几年内，为了满足5G的需求，我们将大幅度地进行升级。
And so sitting at the edge with a mobile edge compute platform that
提供了一个移动边缘计算平台，这样就坐在边缘上，
delivers NDN out of the box.
提供开箱即用的NDN服务。
Is our goal and I think that's our first step and
我们的目标，我认为那是我们的第一步，
really trying to commercialize NDN at least from our optics, right?
我们真的在努力将NDN商业化，至少从我们的视角来看，对吗？
And then applying the the NDN blockchain application solution on top of that
然后在此基础上应用NDN区块链应用解决方案。
to bring in some more automation if you will, so we can validate data flows.
以便我们引入更多的自动化，从而可以验证数据流。
Now, you can validate analytics, immutable records for audits, and tracing and
现在，您可以验证分析数据、不可变的审计记录以及追踪和
all kinds of different things.
各种不同的事物。
So that's really where we sit, we've got a lot of challenges like I said,
所以这正是我们所处的位置，就像我说的，我们面临着很多挑战，
ahead of us.
在我们前方。
But we're getting more and more interest from industry, both in the telecom side.
但我们从工业界得到的兴趣越来越多，包括电信行业。
But then also private industry for hardware and software applications.
但同时也包括了硬件和软件应用的私营行业。
>> Okay, thanks, Justin, let's go through everybody, and
好的，谢谢，贾斯汀，我们来看看每个人的情况，然后
then we'll take some questions at the end or you can even question each other.
然后我们最后会留些时间回答问题，或者你们甚至可以互相提问。
So next up is Dan Massey and Dan is the program lead to
接下来是Dan Massey，Dan是项目负责人，负责的是
the operate through portion of the DODs 5G to next G initiatives.
该项目是国防部从5G到下一代技术（Next G）计划的运作部分。
He was previously a faculty member at Colorado Boulder and
他之前是科罗拉多博尔德的一名教职员工，并且
program manager for the Cyber Security Division Science and
负责网络安全事业部科学与
Technology directorate, that's the CST.
技术总监，那是CST。
Yeah, and in the Department of Homeland Security as a CSP program manager,
是的，在国土安全部担任CSP项目经理，
he developed and manage programs where researchers from both academics and
他开发并管理了一些项目，这些项目中既有学术界的研究人员，也有来自工业界的研究人员，共同识别、解决并部署网络安全解决方案，以应对来自
industry, identify, address and deploy cyber security solutions that
行业界的研究人员，共同识别、解决并部署网络安全解决方案，以提高互联网的安全性和韧性。
improves the security and resilience of the Internet.
提高互联网的安全性和韧性。
And Dan was one of the original NSF FIA NDN project.
丹是最初的NSF FIA NDN项目之一。
Okay, Dan.
好的，丹。
Great. Well, thank you.
非常好。谢谢你。
I really appreciate the opportunity to be here.
我非常感梨有机会来到这里。
And I've got some, I think interesting, new stuff to talk about.
而且我有一些我认为很有趣的新东西要谈。
So as Kathy was just pointing out,
所以正如凯西刚才所指出的，
I've just come on board in the DODs, 5G, the next G initiative.
我刚刚加入了美国国防部的5G和下一代通信技术计划。
And so I'm the program manager for something called can operate through.
所以我是一个名为“能够穿透操作”的项目的项目经理。
And I wanted to kind of say a little bit about what that is and, why I think that's
我想稍微谈谈那是什么，以及我为什么认为那是
particularly relevant to NDN and why we should be talking about that here?
特别与NDN相关，以及为什么我们应该在这里讨论这个问题？
So as you guys already know, right, as already mentioned in
所以正如你们已经知道的，对吧，正如已经提到的，在
Justin stock just a little bit is 5G is coming up pretty quick.
5G的发展正迅速到来。
It's giving us a lot of new opportunities.
它为我们提供了许多新的机会。
And so from the DOD side, we're very interested in how we can leverage that,
因此，从国防部这边来说，我们非常感兴趣的是如何利用这一点，
and how we can do that without thinking in terms of the traditional model.
以及我们如何在不考虑传统模式的情况下做到这一点。
Which I'll claim devolved from the good old Paul Baran multipaths
我将声称这源自保罗·巴兰的多路径理论。
many ways to get there to what, but now is often more of a circuit
有很多方法可以达到目标，但现在通常更多的是一种环路。
based connection and all too often we've relied on that.
我们过于依赖基于连接的方式。
As this community knows well the securing the channel rather than securing the data.
这个社区很清楚，我们更注重保护通道而不是保护数据。
That all goes away if we do it with 5G.
如果我们使用5G来实现，所有这些问题都将不复存在。
So in our vision of 5G in the operate through vision of 5G,
在我们对5G的愿景中，在通过5G的操作视角中，
we're gonna say we have to come and
我们将会说我们必须来到这里并且
we have to operate through existing 5G networks that we don't operate.
我们必须通过我们不运营的现有5G网络来进行操作。
We don't trust, but we need to get sensitive,
我们不信任，但我们需要获取敏感的，
possibly even classified information across those networks.
可能甚至是在那些网络上交换机密信息。
In an environment where I don't know what the network is,
在一个我不知道网络是什么的环境里，
I don't have the network equipment.
我没有网络设备。
The network equipment is manufactured by who knows who's operating it.
网络设备是由谁制造的，谁在操作它我们无从得知。
And so can we operate through that kind of network?
我们能通过那种网络进行操作吗？
That's the SD idea and
这就是SD的想法。
it fits here I think into the edge piece because a lot of this communication
它适合放在边缘部分，因为很多通信工作都是在这里进行的。
in the 5G world especially, there's a lot of interesting stuff on the edge.
在5G世界中，尤其是边缘部分有很多有趣的东西。
Once I get that inside a secure DOD network, that's a different matter.
一旦我把它接入到一个安全的国防部网络中，那就是另外一回事了。
But I've got all these things on the 5G network.
但我已经把所有这些东西都接入到了5G网络中。
At the edge that are gonna need to communicate, they can be vehicles,
在边缘需要进行通信的可以是车辆，
this was discussed earlier.
这个问题之前已经讨论过了。
Earlier today there's a lot of interesting stuff for
今天早些时候有很多有趣的事情要讨论。
those vehicles are gonna be on on 5G networks.
这些车辆将会使用5G网络。
So how does that communication work?
那么这种通信是如何工作的呢？
And how do you do that securely in a zero trust environment?
在零信任环境中，您如何安全地进行这种通信呢？
And I'm gonna, and I think this group might have some answers to that.
我认为这个团队可能对此有一些答案。
So when we say zero trust, I wanna make a slight shift from the really good stuff,
所以当我们谈到零信任时，我想稍微转变一下那些真正好的东西，
thank you to NIST for hosting all this.
感谢NIST主持了这一切。
And NIST has some great documents out there on zero trust.
NIST已经发布了一些关于零信任的优秀文档。
We wanna take a slightly different spin on zero trust in that
我们想对零信任采取略有不同的角度来看待，即
often zero trust is focused on, I operate the network but
通常零信任着重于我操作网络，但
I don't necessarily I don't want to build a wall around my network.
我不一定想在我的网络周围建立一堵墙。
In our case, I wanna take zero trust a step further and
在我们的情况下，我想进一步推进零信任安全模型。
so may even say this is already covered in the NIST documents and
有些人甚至可能会说这已经在NIST文件中有所涉及。
it maybe in this case, I don't even operate the network.
在这种情况下，我甚至可能都不操作网络。
I'm just a user on the network.
我只是网络上的一个用户。
There's all these different paths, all these different knobs I can tune with 5G.
有这么多不同的路径，有这么多不同的旋钮我可以调整来使用5G。
And how do I do that, and somebody posted into, Dave ran posted in,
有人发帖进来，戴夫·兰发帖进来，
do we care about traffic analysis absolutely, right.
我们当然非常关心流量分析。
In fact, I think that's one of our biggest interesting challenges.
实际上，我认为这是我们面临的最大的有趣挑战之一。
And so one thing that we've talked about a lot is, so,
我们经常讨论的一个问题是，所以，
when I talk about securely operating across an untrusted 5G network.
当我谈论在不可信的5G网络上安全操作时。
I'm gonna assume the data is encrypted.
我会假设数据是加密的。
I'm gonna assume that someone can exfiltrate the data but,
我会假设有人能够泄露这些数据，但是，
they can't break the encryption.
他们无法破解加密。
So I'm not too worried about, me sending a confidential
所以我不太担心，我发送一个机密的
message to Justin encrypted with a appropriate cryptography
信息给贾斯汀，用合适的加密技术加密。
that we both share, so who is gonna to get access to that?
我们都有份，那么谁能够获得访问权限呢？
But he's not gonna be able to decrypt it.
但他无法解密它。
>> [LAUGH] I'm the bad guy.
>> [笑] 我是坏人。
>> Yeah.
是的。
We could set defense, we can kind of pick it up.
我们可以设立防御，我们可以尝试去解决它。
But what I am worried about is that traffic analysis.
但我担心的是流量分析。
The analogy we've been using is the pizza deliveries to the pentagon, right?
我们一直在用的比喻是送披萨到五角大楼，对吧？
So, the thought there is by sitting out at the pentagon sitting parking lot across
所以，那里的想法是坐在五角大楼对面的停车场里。
the street from the pentagon and just counting food deliveries in and out.
你可能会通过计算进出五角大楼的食物配送数量来推断出相当多的关于作战节奏的信息。
You may be able to infer quite a bit about operational tempo, right.
你可能会根据这些信息推断出相当多关于作战节奏的事情，对吧。
Friday night, a number of pizzas show up that could be Bob or
周五晚上，出现了一些可能是Bob点的披萨。
Alice's retirement party.
艾丽斯的退休派对。
That could be that means, people are working late and
可能是指，人们在加班工作，还有
there's some kind of hop going on.
可能正在进行某种跳跃活动。
So we're worried about that in this scenario,
所以我们担心在这种情况下，
which is can I operate through this network without revealing too much
我们担心在这种情况下，我是否能够在不泄露太多信息的情况下通过这个网络进行操作，或许有很多方法可以做到这一点，但是。
and maybe there's a bunch of ways I could do that, but.
或许有很多方法可以做到这一点，但是。
But certainly traffic analysis volume metrics are of interest.
但是，流量分析的体量指标肯定会引起人们的兴趣。
And we want to see how that can work.
我们想看看那是如何运作的。
But even more so than on the confidentiality piece,
但比起保密方面，我们更加关注的是——
the availability piece is really the exciting part for us.
我们对可用性部分真的感到很兴奋。
And so with all these different paths, how can I make this work, right.
所以有了这些不同的路径，我该如何使它工作，对吧。
We can do dynamic spectrum allocations, right.
我们可以进行动态频谱分配，对吧。
So unlike our traditional wireless where we're on channel five or channel seven or
所以不像我们传统的无线通信，我们会使用频道五或频道七或者
whatever, we can hop around 5G gives us the ability to hop around,
我们可以在不同频道间跳转，5G赋予我们这种在频道间跳转的能力，
it gives us all these other possibilities.
它为我们提供了所有这些其他的可能性。
It gives us the opportunity to relay but
它给了我们传递信息的机会，但是
I'll tell you that's really hard to do with a circuit, right.
我会告诉你，用电路来做这个真的很难。
There may be some other approach.
也许有其他的方法。
I don't know, maybe there's some other type of networking.
我不知道，可能还有其他类型的网络。
I think, yeah.
我想，是的。
Could be about names or data or something instead of, but so
可能是关于名称或数据或其他的东西，而不是，但是这样。
I think there could be some interesting things there.
我认为那里可能有一些有趣的东西。
So that's just sort of the big picture challenge.
所以那只是一种大局面的挑战。
I wanted to, I wanted to paint is just to say, what
我想要，我只是想要表达的是，什么
about 5G and what about specifically, availability and 5G and
关于5G，具体来说是关于可用性和5G以及
if I can get additional confidentiality and integrity in 5G, that's a bonus.
如果我能在5G中获得额外的保密性和完整性，那就是额外的好处。
But, but I think there's some interesting ways to look at that.
但是，我认为有一些有趣的方式来看待这个问题。
And you'll see last thing and then I'll pass it on to the next panel.
你会看到最后一件事，然后我会把它交给下一个小组。
So you'll see three things coming out of this program.
所以你会看到这个项目带来了三个成果。
It's a brand new program.
这是一个全新的项目。
So we've just added Professor Roy from the University of Washington,
所以我们刚刚邀请了来自华盛顿大学的罗伊教授，
who's a 5G expert.
他是一位5G专家。
So he's running something called Beyond 5G.
所以他在负责一个名为“超越5G”的项目。
What do we do after 5G?
我们在5G之后该做什么？
Cuz 5G won't be the end.
因为5G不会是终点。
I'm running the operate through portion, which is to say, hey,
我正在运行操作部分，也就是说，嘿，
how do I operate on that existing 5G network?
我该如何在现有的5G网络上进行操作？
And there's a group that's currently out there called accelerate,
目前有一个名为accelerate的团队正在那里活动，
which is helping get this adoption into government systems.
它正在帮助推动这种技术在政府系统中的应用。
All three of which, I think could potentially be interesting to NDN.
这三个方面，我认为可能对NDN都有潜在的兴趣。
So I just wanted to kind of put that out there to the group and,
所以我只是想把这些信息告诉大家，
of course the answer any questions.
当然会回答任何问题。
That's it. I think that's it for me.
那就这样吧。我想对我来说就到此为止了。
>> Okay. >> Kathy, I will pass it on the next.
>> 好的。>> 凯西，我会在下一次传递它。
>> Okay, great.
>> 好的，太好了。
Thank you, Dan.
谢谢你，丹。
We'll get back to probably with some questions.
我们可能会提出一些问题再回复您。
Next I'd like to introduce Sokwoo Rhee and he's an entrepreneur and
接下来我想介绍Sokwoo Rhee，他是一位企业家和
executive with expertise in the internet of things, smart cities and
高管，他在物联网、智能城市和无线网络方面拥有专业知识，这些网络适用于商业、工业和军事应用。
wireless networks for commercial, industrial and military applications.
适用于商业、工业和军事应用的无线网络。
He's one of the pioneers who have initiated and
他是最早发起和
grown the IoT industry since the early 2,000's.
推动物联网产业自21世纪初期以来的增长。
He is currently Associate Director for the cyber physical systems innovation
他目前是网络物理系统创新的副主任。
at the National Institute of Standards and Technology are hosting this.
国家标准技术研究院正在主办这个。
And he's been covering enough.
他已经报道得够多了。
Station programs for IoT and Smart Cities.
他负责物联网和智能城市的站点项目。
He manages the global city teams challenge, a US federal government
他管理着全球城市团队挑战赛，这是美国联邦政府的一个项目。
program to develop a global ecosystem of major business and technology stakeholders
旨在发展一个由主要商业和技术利益相关者组成的全球生态系统的项目。
to create replicable and scalable IoT Smart City projects.
旨在创建可复制和可扩展的物联网智能城市项目。
Prior to joining US government, he was co-founder and
在加入美国政府之前，他是联合创始人并且是
CTO of Millennial dot Net Inc.
在Millennial dot Net Inc.担任首席技术官。
One of the first to successfully commercialize low
率先成功商业化低端~!@#$%^&*()
power wireless sensor networks and IoT technologies from Academia.
他的工作和成就已经在包括学术界的多个委员会中得到认可。
His work and achievements have been recognized in multiple boards including
MIT technology reviews top innovators under 35 and he went to MIT.
MIT科技评论评选的35岁以下顶尖创新者之一，他也曾就读于麻省理工学院。
And I would like to give him a chance to speak now, thank you.
我现在想给他一个机会发言，谢谢。
>> Thank you, Kathy, by the way,
>> 谢谢你，顺便说一下，Kathy，
I didn't expect you to read through my whole bio, that wasn't really intention.
我没想到你会把我的整个简历都读一遍，那真的不是我的本意。
And also, I am now much older than 35, that was a long time ago.
而且，我现在比35岁大多了，那是很久以前的事了。
So don't get me wrong for anyone, I don't look like 35.
所以别误会，我看起来不像35岁。
So I didn't even have to say it, so thank you for the intro.
所以我甚至都不需要说了，感谢你的介绍。
So I work on Smart City, I work on large scale IoT in general,
所以我从事智慧城市方面的工作，我通常处理大规模的物联网项目，
but currently Smart Cities is my focus area.
但目前我的重点领域是智慧城市。
Now, I'd like to provide a little bit of perspectives on how sparsity and
现在，我想就稀疏性这一概念提供一些观点，以及它是如何
new networking technologies including edge computing,
新的网络技术包括边缘计算，
can work together or may not work.
可以协同工作，也可能不行。
So there are a lot of buzz about edge computing these days.
如今，边缘计算领域有很多热议。
And then even in the Smart City area,
并且即使在智慧城市领域，
a lot of people are talking about how to use edge computing concepts.
很多人正在讨论如何使用边缘计算概念。
In the context of a Smart City and in many cases,
在智慧城市的背景下，在很多情况下，
that what I see is technologies like me for companies.
我看到的是像我这样的技术被公司所使用。
Basically, bringing this new concept and
基本上，是将这个新概念带入
try to push to the cities and the city officials, in many cases,
努力推广至各个城市及市政官员，在许多情况下，
municipalities are perplex any cases, always gonna help me, right?
市政当局在许多情况下都感到困惑，你总是会帮助我，对吧？
So there's a huge gap between this the actual users, it was Smart City or the,
所以在实际用户与智慧城市之间存在着巨大的差距，或者说，
for lack of a better word, customers that was Smart City technologies.
为了更恰当地表达，可以称之为智慧城市技术的客户。
And the suppliers, and that question is done new here,
供应商也是如此，这个问题在这里已经得到了解决。
it's been around for a long time.
它已经存在很长时间了。
But when it comes to new emerging technologies such as 5G or
但当涉及到5G或者这类新兴技术时，
edge computing, that problem is amplified much bigger.
边缘计算会将那个问题放大很多。
Because edge computing conceptually, the way that typically,
由于从概念上讲，边缘计算的典型方式，
the companies explain that is,
公司解释说，这是，
use that computing you can reduce the bandwidth requirement.
使用那种计算，你可以减少带宽需求。
And the companies make it a big deal, and then say, so
而公司们把它当作一件大事，然后说，所以
you have to install edge computing capabilities in a city, and
你必须在一个城市中安装边缘计算能力，而且
then city officials go, okay, why should I worry about it?
然后城市官员会说，好吧，我为什么要担心这个问题呢？
Only reason I should worry about is because I got to pay more for
我唯一需要担心的原因是因为我得付更多的钱。
the cell network, cell bandwidth.
移动网络，蜂窝带宽。
That's really, then question comes down to, okay, if I install this devices,
那真的是，然后问题归结为，好的，如果我安装这些设备，
are you saying that I don't need to use cell network to get to the edge compute?
您是在说我不需要使用蜂窝网络就能连接到边缘计算吗？
So the last mile problem is still not solved,
所以最后一公里的问题仍然没有解决，
because you cannot use WiFi because there's too
因为WiFi信号太弱，所以你不能使用WiFi。
short in city environment in a whole environment, it may be okay.
在整个城市环境中可能还可以，但在局部城市环境中信号就弱了。
But it gets down to broad Metropolitan environment,
但在更广泛的大都市环境中，
you still cannot really avoid relying on a cell network,
你仍然无法真正避免依赖蜂窝网络，
even if your edge devices are built in.
即使你的边缘设备是内置的。
So the point I'm making is this, in Smart City area,
所以我要表达的观点是，在智慧城市领域，
edge computing is a 5G's buzzwords.
边缘计算是5G的热门词汇。
I think there is still time and there is a gap in adoption,
我认为还有时间，而且在采纳方面还存在差距。
especially, it's computing 5G.
尤其是它的5G计算技术。
I think is gonna happen much quicker, because Apple no matter what, and
我认为这将会发生得更快，因为无论如何，苹果公司……
frankly speaking, the carriers will not want to let us not have 5G.
坦白说，运营商是不会允许我们不使用5G的。
They wanna simply just keep manufacturing devices on 5G, replace it with
他们只是想简单地继续生产支持5G的设备，用它来替换掉
the 4G device and we weren't enough, I have a lot of choice out there.
我们不满足于4G设备，我有很多其他的选择。
But when you come into the municipal network or municipalities,
但当你进入市政网络或市政当局时，
who are probably the bigger customer, that's a little bit different.
他们可能是较大的客户，这有一点不同。
Because they may still, although, networks are still operating in 2G network.
因为他们可能仍然在使用，尽管网络仍在2G网络下运行。
A lot of people, many people, not many people know why, but
很多人，许多人，并不是很多人知道为什么，但是
a lot of them are still running on 2G or even 3G networks.
很多人仍在使用2G甚至3G网络。
So point as for edge computing and NDN too,
这些新概念，如边缘计算和NDN（命名数据网络），也想要进入主流。
these kinda new concepts to wanna get into the mainstream.
这些新概念也想要进入主流。
I think we need to have a very clear pitch, and
我认为我们需要有一个非常清晰而有说服力的信息。
very clear and convincing message.
非常清晰而有说服力的信息。
Why this new technologies we're gonna help municipalities to operate and
这些新技术将帮助市政机构运作并且
deliver their services, and fulfill their mission.
提供他们的服务，并完成他们的使命。
I'm gonna stop there for now.
我现在就先停在这里。
>> Okay, thank you, and thanks for introducing this idea that maybe
好的，谢谢你，也感谢你提出这个想法，或许
we need to think about creating applications which have some pull
我们需要考虑创建一些具有吸引力的应用程序。
instead of trying to push them on people who might not want them.
而不是试图将它们强加给那些可能不需要它们的人。
So maybe we're looking in the wrong places, so-
所以也许我们在错误的地方寻找，所以-
>> Wow, you summarized it, I spent 10
哇，你总结了它，我花了10分钟讲了很多，你却在[笑声] [听不清]中把它概括得太棒了。
minutes talking a lot, you summarized it in [LAUGH] [INAUDIBLE], awesome.
分钟讲了很多，你却在[笑声] [听不清]中把它概括得太棒了。
>> No, no, you are very good, thank you.
不，不，你做得非常好，谢谢你。
Next, I'd like to introduce Dr. Geng Wu and he's an Intel fellow and
接下来，我想介绍吴耿博士，他是英特尔的资深院士，同时也是
a Chief Technologist for wireless technologies and standards.
他是无线技术和标准的首席技术专家。
He leads Intel's 5G and 6G technology development and ecosystem collaboration.
他领导英特尔的5G和6G技术开发以及生态系统合作。
Okay, that's what comes after 5G, I guess,
好吧，我猜那就是5G之后的事情了。
he serves as the head of Intel's delegation to 3GPP.
他担任英特尔公司代表团的团长，参与3GPP。
And he's a director of the board of the IOWN Global Forum,
他还是IOWN全球论坛董事会的一员。
the multi-fire alliance and the automotive edge computing consortium.
多火盟和汽车边缘计算联盟。
everything at the edge, go ahead, your turn.
一切尽在掌握之中，往前走，轮到你了。
>> Thank you very much, so it is my great honor to be here and
非常感谢，能来到这里是我的莫大荣幸，
well, if there's no virus situation,
嗯，如果没有病毒情况的话，
we would be having a drink with the co-panelists after the session.
我们会在会议结束后和其他小组成员一起喝一杯。
Excited to be here, so let's me just
很高兴来到这里，所以让我简单地
say a few words about why I'm here.
说几句关于我为什么会来这里的原因。
So the topic that this particular session is addressing,
所以这个特定的会议要讨论的主题是，
it's actually very interesting.
这实际上非常有趣。
Internet of Things and edge,
物联网和边缘计算，
both are very much to the heart of the 5G industry.
这两者都是5G行业的核心所在。
And also the next upgrade platform upgrade that in the next ten years,
我们还在致力于下一个十年的平台升级。
we're working certainly on the next generation.
我们当然也在致力于下一代的工作。
So there's some fundamental technology drivers supposes,
所以有一些基础技术驱动假设存在，
for example, the need for network performance,
例如，对网络性能的需求，
as well as the localization of machine intelligence and
以及机器智能的本地化与
machine learning are really driving the networking and
机器学习确实在推动网络发展，
computing functions for the network edge.
为网络边缘提供计算功能。
Having said so, there is also assumption,
已经这么说了，也存在着假设，
kind of in common between these two important,
这两个重要的东西之间有某种共通之处，
probably the most important aspect of the technology development for
可能是技术发展最重要的方面是
this and the next generation, which is that
这一代和下一代最重要的是，
The solutions are well we do see,
我们确实看到了解决方案是，
in both cases we have the fragmented the design and
在这两种情况下，我们都将设计进行了碎片化处理，
the solutions and so basically basically different optimizations.
解决方案以及基本上不同的优化。
And quite often we see the issues that
我们经常会看到这些问题，
yes, these solutions are hard to scale and
是的，这些解决方案很难扩展，并且
some of the panelists the colleagues here already mentioned that.
一些在场的小组成员和同事们已经提到了这一点。
So basically, how do we actually horizontalise the technology and
那么基本上，我们如何实际上将技术横向扩展，
more importantly the market at the industry?
更重要的是，行业市场怎么样？
That's probably one of the key issues that we need to address.
这可能是我们需要解决的关键问题之一。
If you look deeper from a purely technology viewpoint,
如果你从纯粹技术的角度更深入地看，
I think most of the issues really come in from the fact that we
我认为大多数问题实际上都源自我们所处理的事情，它们涉及到计算和发展。
are dealing with a evolve the computing and
涉及到计算和发展演变。
networking and data model.
网络和数据模型。
So that's a particular model actually, that drives the way we design the network,
所以这实际上是一个特定的模型，它引导了我们设计网络的方式。
we did our platform.
我们开发了我们的平台。
We did our applications as part of actually evolving.
我们开发我们的应用程序作为实际进化的一部分。
To be more specific, for example, we do expect
为了更具体一点，例如，我们确实期待
the next generation system to be platform to be at least order for
下一代系统将是一个平台，至少要比现在快一个数量级。
magnitude faster than what we have today.
要比我们现在拥有的快一个数量级。
We are seeing that the network,
我们正在看到网络，
the switching fabric for example, increasingly programmable even today,
例如，交换网络，即使在今天，也越来越可编程，
we can easily do one single part.
我们可以轻松完成单一部分。
This terabit is for multi terabits per second, fully programmable switching.
这个太比特是用于每秒多太比特的全可编程交换。
So that's not an issue.
所以那不是问题。
So there's it, that's a tremendous the technology opportunities there.
所以就是这样，那里有巨大的技术机遇。
We also see the challenges.
我们也看到了挑战。
We need to have a deeper understanding of
我们需要对此有更深入的了解。
the computer communication and
计算机通信和
the data model, what that means and
数据模型是什么意思以及
how the NDN play a critical enabling role in this new word?
NDN在这个新世界中扮演了怎样关键的启用角色？
Network obviously is no longer just a communication pipe that
显然，网络不再仅仅是一个通信管道，它还能够
connects the two ends.
连接两端。
Is so tremendous your networking, computing and data processing.
你的网络、计算和数据处理能力是如此巨大。
So those things are actually the cool thing is that NDN was
实际上很酷的是，NDN是
actually very much designed from the very beginning to serve.
实际上从一开始就非常精心设计来服务。
To actually assume that the network is suggesting not just
实际上假设网络不仅仅是在暗示
a collection of communication pipes, so that's important.
一系列的通讯管道，这很重要。
I think Dan touched on the fact that the zero
我认为丹提到了零信任是因为NDN的设计方式。
trust was because of the way NDN was designed.
信任是因为NDN的设计方式。
That there are some unique capabilities,
这是因为有一些独特的能力，
that security capabilities that enable us to do something different,
那些安全能力使我们能够做一些不同的事情，
and those are the areas that we are looking forward to
和那些是我们期待的领域。
work with the research community and to to address and
与研究社区合作以解决和应对
that's the reason why we are very much a strong supporter and
这就是为什么我们非常支持并且
passionate about the technology.
对技术充满热情。
Back to you, Nicole.
回到你这里，Nicole。
>> Okay, what I guess I should there's one question I have here this very
好的，我想我应该在这里有一个问题，这个问题非常
specifically for Justin and let's do that and we'll see if any others come up and
专门针对贾斯汀，我们就这么做，然后我们会看看是否还有其他问题出现。
see what we can talk about what among ourselves.
看看我们能讨论些什么。
If we'd like to know how far along is the NDN plus block chain solution and
如果我们想了解NDN加区块链解决方案的发展进度，以及
what aspects are furthest along development, prototype,s deployed, etc?
哪些方面的开发进展最快，已部署原型等？
>> Yeah, so we finished we finished the minimum viable product and
是的，所以我们完成了最小可行产品并且
kind of proof of concept early last year.
去年早些时候我们完成了一种概念验证。
So we've been continuing to develop that product, though, so that the original
所以我们一直在继续开发那个产品，以便原始的
genesis block was created over a year ago, almost a year and a half ago now.
创世区块是在一年多前创建的，现在几乎一年半了。
And so now we're at the stage where we're actually deploying that in test beds,
所以现在我们正处于一个阶段，即实际上在测试环境中部署该应用。
like I said, so we're gonna be taking part of that application and
像我说的，所以我们将会把那个应用的一部分
deploying it in our mobile edge compute platform.
部署在我们的移动边缘计算平台上。
And then we also have a separate standalone application that's primarily
我们还有一个独立的应用程序，它主要是
just gonna be used for localized payment processing.
仅用于本地化支付处理。
And so, we're doing that.
所以，我们正在做这个。
So where you can actually take and just install this on like a Raspberry Pi or
所以你实际上可以把它安装在类似树莓派这样的设备上。
whatever, right?
无论如何，对吧？
And then but the idea right is that you have everything localized your web server,
然后，但是想法是，你已经将你的网页服务器全部本地化了，
your APIs, everything's localized right?
你的API也全部本地化了，对吧？
And eventually where we wanna get to with this is we wanna have the entire
最终我们想要达到的目标是我们想要拥有一个完整的
front end application built with NDN, right?
基于NDN构建的前端应用程序，对吗？
Built on top of NDN.
基于NDN之上构建的。
And so right now we're just using it as kind of like a middleware.
所以现在我们只是将它作为一种中间件来使用。
And we're just passing it through the satellite network and
我们只是通过卫星网络传输它。
or any other network that we're kinda using, right?
或者我们正在使用的任何其他网络，对吗？
But we're trying to prove out that we can use NDN across a satellite link here
但我们正在尝试证明我们可以在这里通过卫星链路使用NDN。
in the next couple of weeks with our block-chain application.
在接下来的几周里，我们将使用我们的区块链应用程序。
And then I think the next steps for that right is that to kinda go
接下来，我认为正确的步骤是继续去做。
back to kinda some of the things Dan brought up as well.
我们也要回到丹提出的一些问题上。
We're looking at that blockchain application in the mobile edge compute
我们正在研究移动边缘计算中的区块链应用。
platform for auditing, primarily, right?
主要是用于审计的平台，对吧？
Assurance is a big one.
保证是一个重要的方面。
On-boarding is another huge one.
引入新用户是另一个非常重要的方面。
So, we've got to be able to take that blockchain application and
所以，我们必须能够将那个区块链应用程序进行调整，
have it vanilla enough to where we can apply it to those types of scenarios.
将其设计得足夜通用，以便我们能够将其应用到那些类型的场景中。
Or now we we can say, hey look, we can use zero knowledge proofs to validate
或者现在我们可以说，嘿看，我们可以使用零知识证明来验证
that the identity of this user is who they say they are without exposing their entire
身份信息，确保这个用户就是他们所声称的那个人，而无需暴露他们的全部
privacy, but also at the same time validating that the traffic and
隐私，同时还要验证通过网络的数据是稳定的。
the data that's coming through the network is not volatile.
通过网络的数据不是易失的。
It's not gonna cause problems.
它不会引起问题。
It's not gonna take the network down.
它不会导致网络瘫痪。
It doesn't have kinda some nasty payloads and some stuff in there as well.
它里面也没有包含一些恶意的负载和其他东西。
And that really speaks more to the military and
这实际上更多地涉及到军事方面。
government applications we're that seeing for requests for
我们正在看到政府应用程序的请求，用于
a verifiable trace routes, auditing assurance for whether you're
可验证的追踪路径，无论你是否在进行审计保证，
spinning up applications or Kubernetes clusters or whatever that case might be.
部署应用程序或Kubernetes集群，或者其他任何可能的情况。
But All those RF
但所有那些射频
kind of like spectrum analytics are gonna have to have auditing trails as well.
这些类似于频谱分析的技术也将不得不有审计追踪。
The FCC is pushing for that.
美国联邦通信委员会（FCC）正在推动这一进程。
So a lot of these different mandates that are coming down from not just governments,
这些不同的法令不仅仅来自政府，
but also from private industry as well.
还包括私营行业的法令。
And then also the the governing bodies like 3GPP and all these other things.
还有3GPP和其他这些管理机构。
So we're looking at that.
所以我们正在研究这个问题。
We're saying hey, you know, next steps for us is we really have to make
我们在说，嘿，你知道的，我们的下一步真的必须要做的是
the blockchain application deployed on the mobile edge compute platform.
将区块链应用部署在移动边缘计算平台上。
And now we can really open it up to all those IoT based applications to
现在我们确实可以将其全面开放给所有基于物联网的应用程序。
start off with.
我们可以从这里开始。
Now, because there's a huge developer pool out there that we're pulling in from
现在，因为外面有一个庞大的开发者群体，我们正在吸引他们加入。
Nvidia and Intel and some others, right?
英伟达、英特尔还有一些其他公司，对吗？
So we're gonna be able to enable those applications to run at the edge.
所以我们将能够使那些应用程序在边缘运行。
And then that's gonna give us the ability to work with industry and regulating
然后这将使我们有能力与行业和监管机构合作。
bodies and everybody involved, to really make sure that we can go to the DOD and
向所有相关机构和每一个参与者确保我们能够前往国防部。
say, Hey, here's an option for you if you want to deploy this on network.
说，嘿，如果你想在网络上部署这个，这里有一个选项可以提供给你。
To verify your routes, you can, are all the different analytics that you need or
为了验证你的路由，你可以使用所有你需要的不同分析工具。
zero proof knowledge kind of applications as well.
零知识证明类型的应用程序也是如此。
Thanks, Justin.
谢谢，贾斯汀。
There was a question that I think you already answered, Dan,
有一个问题我认为你已经回答了，丹，
that came up from Dave around about the traffic analysis.
但那引出了戴夫关于交通分析的一些问题。
But that brought up something for
但那引出了一些问题，
me that back when Van was first talking about what became NDN.
这让我想起了早先范首次提到后来成为NDN的事情时的情形。
I was consulting to this Airforce thing called TMOS,
我曾为一项名为TMOS的空军项目提供咨询服务，
which was a satellite based network that was servicing all these military networks.
该项目是一个基于卫星的网络，用于服务所有这些军用网络。
And the chief architect of that was really interested in this idea because of
他说，你可以发送流量的这个有些违反直觉的想法，因为这位总设计师对此非常感兴趣。
the somewhat counter-intuitive idea that he said, you can send traffic
他说，你可以发送流量的这个有些违反直觉的想法
in all different directions, not just where you want it to go.
向各个不同的方向发送，而不仅仅是你想要它去的地方。
So I guess it'd be like you sending pizzas all over DC or
所以我猜这就像你把披萨送遍整个华盛顿特区一样，或者
something [LAUGH] or sending pizzas every Friday.
或者每周五送披萨之类的事情。
And I mean that's sort of, we think about efficiency.
我是说，这在某种程度上，我们考虑的是效率。
But I mean what do you think about that idea is that that's sort of
但我是说，你对那个观点怎么看？就是说，这在某种程度上是
the opposite of efficiency, but it's sort of obscuring what's really going on.
效率的反面，但在某种程度上它模糊了真正发生的事情。
>> Yeah, I think that's a great example.
是的，我认为那是一个很好的例子。
I think there's a lot of interesting potential there where, and
我认为那里存在很多有趣的潜力，其中，
back to sort of what I've always taken sort of as the NDN mantra is it's very
回到我一直认为的NDN的口头禅，那就是它非常
hard to hide that volumetrics when it's a point to point circuit, right.
难以隐藏那种体积度量，当它是点对点电路的时候，对吧。
Cuz it's hard to say, but as you point out, right, we could
因为这很难说，但正如你所指出的，我们可以
with 5G there may be applications where I've got enough bandwidth and
在5G环境下，可能会有一些应用场景，我拥有足够的带宽并且
I actually don't care if I'm burning some additional bandwidth.
实际上，我并不介意如果我消耗了一些额外的带宽。
So I don't care if I'm sending data in random directions.
所以我并不在乎我是否在向随机的方向发送数据。
I like your example of I might just call up Domino's in Arlington,
我可能会打电话给阿灵顿的Domino's。
Virginia and send pizzas to 20 different directions and who knows.
弗吉尼亚可能会向20个不同的方向发送披萨，谁知道呢。
So that's a real possibility.
所以那是一个真正的可能性。
And so
我们正在试图摆脱那种能够轻易识别出来源的想法。
we're trying to get away from that idea of being able to easily identify the source.
Another example that's come up is, yeah, I have all these devices,
另一个出现的例子是，是的，我有所有这些设备，
they could serve as relays, they could serve as.
它们可以作为中继站，它们可以作为。
I could talk to Kathy via anyone on this conference,
我可以通过这次会议上的任何人与Kathy交谈，
maybe via 20 of you on this conference, and then.
也许通过在这次会议上的你们中的20个人，然后。
So it's interesting to see what you could hide if you put aside
所以，如果你把某些东西放在一边，看看你能隐藏些什么，这是很有趣的。
the goal of I don't have limited bandwidth, I have plenty of bandwidth.
我的目标不是拥有有限的带宽，而是拥有充足的带宽。
I don't have a small number of paths, I have plenty of paths.
我不是拥有少量的路径，而是拥有很多的路径。
Does that give me some new advantages?
这是否给了我一些新的优势？
Maybe it does.
也许它确实如此。
And yeah.
是的。
>> Done on mute.
>> 静音完成。
Sokwoo, it looks like you wanted to say something.
Sokwoo，看起来你好像想说点什么。
>> Yes, thank you.
是的，谢谢。
I want to say because this is fascinating idea.
我想说这是一个迷人的想法。
By the way, Dan, welcome back to federal government, by the way,
顺便说一句，丹，欢迎回到联邦政府。
good to have you back.
很高兴你回来了。
So from DOD perspective, it may not be,
从国防部的角度来看，可能不是这样的，
you may not need to be in the situation that you have a lot of bandwidth.
你可能不需要处于你有大量带宽的情况。
You may have still limited bandwidth but
你可能仍然有限的带宽，但
you were willing to pay for it because it may be more secure in certain cases.
你愿意为此付费，因为在某些情况下它可能更安全。
It's like military is not always inexpensive,
军事并不总是便宜的，
the way you need the best and you need the most secure, most powerful.
你需要最好的，也需要最安全、最强大的。
So especially for DOD title applications, makes perfect sense.
所以特别是对于国防部头衔应用来说，这是完全合理的。
Well, you don't have to really think about efficiency as much as partial world.
嗯，你不必像部分世界那样真的过分考虑效率。
And probably you don't want to prioritize efficiency over other important factors.
可能你不想把效率置于其他重要因素之上。
So makes perfect sense, and actually just wanted, I mean this is intriguing you
这完全有道理，实际上我只是想说，我的意思是这真的很有趣。
interpret that always [LAUGH] because we've been always thinking about this
解释这总是因为我们一直在思考这个问题。[笑]
we have to talk to talk about the security of the device or the manufacturer.
我们必须讨论设备或制造商的安全性。
That's why we're having all this discussions about, you know what.
这就是为什么我们要就这个话题进行所有这些讨论。
But that's sort of like a whack a mole game.
但这有点像打地鼠游戏。
I mean, about validate one device is secure, but
我是说，关于验证一个设备的安全性，但是
there may be other manufacturers that you may not be able to validate as secure.
可能还有其他制造商的设备你无法验证其安全性。
So you cannot, and
所以你不能够。
this is sort of like an endless dilemma that you're gonna eventually face.
这就像是一个你最终将不得不面对的无休止的困境。
So probably the better approach,
所以可能更好的方法是，
Dan, as you mentioned is let's assume that everybody's insecure.
丹，正如你提到的，让我们假设每个人都不安全。
Let's assume all devices are insecure.
让我们假设所有设备都是不安全的。
Let's find a way still do our job on top of this
让我们找到一种方法在这种情况下仍然完成我们的工作。
less secure, assumed less secure network.
较不安全的，假定是不安全的网络。
That's a fascinating approach.
这是一个引人入胜的方法。
That could solve, if you could come up with something really, really real,
这可能会有所解决，如果你能想出一些真正非常真实的东西，
that could solve a lot of the dilemma that we have right now.
这可能会解决我们现在面临的许多困境。
>> Thank you.
>> 谢谢。
And a lot of this credit goes to my boss, Joe Evans, who Dr.
很多功劳要归于我的老板，Joe Evans博士，他……
Joe Evans, who's put the big structure for the program in place.
Joe Evans博士，他为该项目建立了整体架构。
But I do think this is a, I do think there's a interesting way to
但我确实认为，我确实认为有一种有趣的方式来
think about this a little bit differently and to get out of the old mode.
思考这个问题有一点不同，跳出旧有的模式。
And that's why I'm particularly interested in talking on this group,
这也是我特别感兴趣想在这个群里交谈的原因，
right, because I think it
对，因为我认为它
also helps to have an architecture that's thinking along different lines.
它还有助于拥有一个沿着不同思路设计的架构。
And it's a whole different matter to say how do I hide
而说到如何隐藏这件事，则是另外一回事了。
the fact that source A is talking to destination B, when I've kind of got rid
关于源头A正在与目的地B对话这一事实，当我某种程度上摆脱了源头与目的地这一概念，并且更多地转向了内容时。
of the idea of source and destination and I've changed more to content.
所以，我认为这里有一些真正有趣的潜力。
So yeah, so I think there's some real interesting potential.
So hopefully, hopefully there'll be some fun stuff that comes out of this and
所以希望，希望这一切能带来一些有趣的东西。
we hope to get some interest.
我们希望能够引起一些兴趣。
But even if it's not for a DOD setting, and Sokwoo is exactly right,
但即使不是为了国防部的设置，Sokwoo 说得完全正确，
at a DOD setting they can pay for, security is worth the price there.
在国防部的环境中，他们能够支付得起，那里的安全是值得付出代价的。
So we can pay for some of those resources.
所以我们可以支付那些资源的费用。
But even in not a VOD setting, right,
但即便不是在视频点播的环境中，对吧，
this idea of the added agility in the 5G network.
这个关于5G网络增加敏捷性的想法。
And can we take advantage of that?
我们能够利用这一点吗？
And again, with this panel being focused on the edge,
而且再次强调，由于这个小组专注于边缘计算，
a lot of that communication in those smart cities, in the vehicles, in the blockchain
在智慧城市中、车辆中、区块链上的许多通信，
authentication is really going to, can really happen substantially at the edges.
认证实际上将会、确实可以在边缘处大量发生。
And how does that work?
这是如何运作的？
And it doesn't work well if I put it in a centralized model where it will all go
如果我把它放在一个中心化模型里，它就不会工作得很好。
back to the, let's send it all back to the central server and let's do it.
回到那个问题，让我们把所有数据都发送回中央服务器，然后再处理。
It works well in a distributed manner,
它在分布式环境下运行得很好，
which I think is well suited to do a lot of what the NDN communities.
我认为它非常适合完成许多NDN社区的工作。
>> Do any of you have maybe just any particular
您中有人有没有什么特别的想法？
charges that you would say to the NDN research community?
您认为对NDN研究社区特别重要的问题是什么？
Things that you feel like would be particularly
您觉得会特别
good to look at that seem to be neglected areas?
您觉得会特别值得关注的似乎被忽视了的领域？
Go back to that push versus pull model,
回到那个推与拉的模型，
what things would pull you in if you saw somebody working on that?
如果你看到有人在做那件事，什么东西会吸引你？
It would make you kind of go, wow.
它会让你有种“哇”的感觉。
That's a great thing.
这是一件很棒的事情。
>> I've got some.
>> 我有一些。
>> Yeah. >> Wait, let's see.
>> 是的。 >> 等等，我们看看。
Let's start with Geng Wu, he hasn't spoken for us yet.
我们从耿武开始吧，他还没为我们发言呢。
>> Okay, thank you.
好的，谢谢。
So there's several things.
所以有几件事情。
First of all, I would like to echo the and dance comments.
首先，我想回应一下之前的评论。
In fact, even for commercial systems,
实际上，即使对于商业系统来说，
the security is increasingly critical due to the nature of the network and
网络的性质使得安全性变得日益重要，由于
also the fact that the We are seeing the rapid
我们正在见证迅速
growth of private network, enterprise network and
私有网络、企业网络的快速增长，以及
mission critical even from a commercial point of view.
对于商业角度来说，这也是至关重要的。
So, how to actually make
那么，如何实际去做呢？
the insight of secure the session security connection?
如何确保会话安全连接的洞察？
How about directly security data snd how about protecting privacy?
如何直接保护数据安全以及如何保护隐私？
So those are the one of the things that really,
所以那些是真正重要的事情之一，
we need a research community is how to father and son.
我们需要一个研究社区来探讨父与子的关系。
There are 2, there's a section for Nikko side to the question I said,
您有两个问题，其中一个是关于日光方面的问题。
What's the otherwise you have for the research community?
您对研究社区还有什么其他建议吗？
I think there's 2 ways to look at it.
我认为可以从两个角度来看待这个问题。
One way is to understand
从一个角度是去理解
the opportunities that I think that Dan actually touched on that,
我认为丹实际上提到了的那些机会，
the next generation we are going to upgrade dramatically
我们将对下一代进行大幅升级。
the network performance from device to network and to fabric.
设备到网络再到架构的网络性能。
So instead of trying to save every bit and then.
所以不是试图节省每一点然后。
What would it be Indians technology potential,
印度的技术潜力会是什么呢？
because the way is doing things are dramatically different.
因为做事的方式截然不同。
What would the diet gave us assuming that you are running
如果你在跑步，那么这种饮食会给我们带来什么假设？
the next generation network.
下一代网络。
So that's the last aspect.
所以那是最后一个方面。
To be more specific.
要更具体一些。
The other aspect is the things that we were very much interested in.
另一个方面是我们非常感兴趣的事情。
Is to look at Indian as a tool as an opportunity
是将印第安作为一个工具、一个机会来看待。
for the network to go a status and professionalize.
为了使网络达到一种状态并专业化。
There's this are 2 separate things but people often call the London together.
这是两个不同的事物，但人们常常把它们统称为伦敦。
Stay less means that since your service are more localized and
停留时间短意味着你的服务更加本地化，而且
you're going at the edge, etc, etc so and also we're going very high frequency band,
你正在边缘进行操作等等，所以我们也在使用非常高的频段，
they have a millimeter wave, they have a terahertz coming up and
他们有毫米波，他们还在研发太赫兹技术，
then the connectivity really is not always there.
那么连接性并不总是存在的。
Is probably more opportunistic.
可能更多的是机会主义的。
And then the question is, what are the technology really to make that work?
那么问题就是，到底需要什么技术来实现这一切呢？
And so the night one devices need to go stay less and session, less.
那么夜间设备需要变得更加省电和更少的会话。
Well, can you actually build the security around?
那么，你真的可以围绕它构建安全措施吗？
More independent from the session itself inside of?
它在会话本身内部更加独立吗？
So there's many, many benefits.
所以有很多很多的好处。
I think that my co-panelists already addressed so I wouldn't, so, repeater.
我认为我的联席专家们已经讨论过了，所以我不会重复他们的话。
So I think, one thing we probably want to work on to the research
所以我认为，我们可能想要在研究上努力工作的一件事是
community to help us is to understand the new computing communication data model.
社区帮助我们理解新的计算通信数据模型。
And assuming you have a next generation platform, and
假设你有一个下一代平台，以及……
how you latter would make the MDN divinely help us to
如何让MDN在以后能够神圣地帮助我们……
build the next generation system and that benefit everyone.
构建下一代系统，使每个人都能从中受益。
Thank you.
谢谢您。
>> Yeah, thank you.
是的，谢谢您。
>> Does anybody else have something to add on that one?
>> 还有谁想对这个问题补充点什么吗？
>> Yeah, let me go next, and then I know Justin wanna jump in too.
>> 嗯，让我接下来说，然后我知道贾斯汀也想插话。
But I talk a lot, Justin, just smile, I like your smile.
但我话挺多的，贾斯汀，你就笑笑吧，我喜欢你的笑容。
And [LAUGH] so gain, I work on smart cities.
所以，再次强调，我研究智能城市。
So one of the biggest issues in our city especially from the perspective of data,
所以从数据的角度来看，我们城市面临的最大问题之一，
is this lack of interoperability even inside of the city operation.
这种缺乏互操作性甚至存在于城市运营的内部。
So what I mean by that is that the transportation department may have their
所以我的意思是交通部门可能有他们自己的
own data sets and their own communication, and connectivity mechanisms.
自己的数据集合以及他们自己的通信和连接机制。
But the packets and
但是数据包和
data are not necessarily packed in that there's no content.
数据并不一定是打包的，也就是说并非没有内容。
So typically if you use this communicate or
所以通常情况下，如果你使用这种沟通方式或者
system if just inside of department is okay because it's not from the when
如果只是在部门内部使用还可以，因为它并不是来自于那个时候。
want to create a smart city system which is cutting across all different sectors?
想要创建一个跨越所有不同领域的智能城市系统？
Suddenly it the data format, or the the packing of the data becomes a big issue.
突然间，数据的格式或者数据打包成了一个大问题。
So, I'm not necessarily getting down to the network layer or
所以，我不一定要深入到网络层，或者
even below I'm not getting the data by more talking about application level.
甚至更低层次，我也不是通过更多的交谈来获取数据，而是更多地谈论应用层级。
But one of the biggest problems we are seeing is data packets,
但我们看到的最大问题之一是数据包，
which is typically the tag with IP address,
通常是带有IP地址的标签，
some kind of address and the context over the content is completely separate.
某种类型的地址以及内容上下文是完全分开的。
And that is causing a lot of problems in developing a more holistic,
这正在导致在开发更全面的方面出现很多问题，
smart city data exchange network.
智能城市数据交换网络。
So I'm not necessarily thing that is the problem and
所以我不一定认为那是问题所在。
the network is going to be able to solve like a silver bullet.
网络将能够像银色子弹一样解决问题。
But point is, that's the problem I'm seeing from the Smart Cities perspective.
但问题是，从智慧城市的角度来看，这正是我所看到的问题。
If there is anything that end in network can contribute.
如果有任何事情是网络可以贡献的。
Addressing it, perhaps bring that concept into data exchange platform that is
解决这个问题，或许可以将这个概念引入到数据交换平台。
being developed by so many different cities and states and governments.
正在被众多不同的城市、州和政府开发。
That could potentially change the game.
这可能会改变游戏规则。
I'm just throwing that out.
我只是随便说说的。
That's right, Justin [LAUGH] >> Yeah,
对，Justin [笑声] >> 是的，
I'll be brief I totally agree with you guys and
我会简短地说，我完全同意你们的观点，
I think it's really important for us to focus on on the bigger picture.
我认为我们专注于更宏观的大局非常重要。
Whenever we're looking forward right and so anywhere we can we can pull those
无论何时我们都在向前看，因此我们可以利用任何机会去拉动那些把手，通过这样的方式在小范围内甚至大范围内改善事物。
levers and kind of improve things on a small scale or even on a big scale.
杠杆，并且在小规模甚至大规模上改善事物。
That's really where we should be focused.
这确实是我们应该集中关注的地方。
And I think for me, right, because I'm up in the weeds for the most part right now
而且我认为，对我来说，是这样的，因为目前我大部分时间都在处理琐碎的事务。
currently, but I think the forwarder is kind of our biggest challenge right now.
但我认为目前最大的挑战是货运代理。
And so if we could look at it, you know,
如果我们能够仔细看看这个问题，你知道的，
I think it was hit on some of the previous discussions where we can, you know, it.
我认为这在之前的一些讨论中已经被提及过，我们可以，你知道的，它。
And the reason I say that is because if you look at how 5G works and
而我之所以这么说，是因为如果你研究一下5G是如何工作的，以及
dynamic slot you know just the slicing are long right and
动态时隙，你知道的，就是长时间的切片，还有
like we're looking at dynamic slicing, you've got a bunch of other things
像我们在看动态切片，你还得考虑许多其他事项。
that go into the like the the slicing aspects of it to right?
这些都是进入切片方面需要考虑的，对吗？
But moving forward into 5G and moving forward into those types of
但展望未来，进入5G以及那些类型的
networks where you've got slicing and you've got CBR s in there too, right?
网络中有分片技术，也有CBR，对吧？
Where you've got different allocations for different uses.
在那里，你有不同的分配用于不同的用途。
So we're really, we're getting down to network utilization spectrum utilization,
所以我们真的在深入研究网络利用率、频谱利用率。
but whenever you look at that from a forwarder standpoint.
但是当你从一个转发器的角度来看这个问题时。
Being able to create dynamic faces on the fly for thousands or millions of devices,
能够即时为成千上万的设备创建动态面孔，
or thousands of millions of users, and being able to do that and
在成千上万甚至数以百万计的用户中做到这一点，并且能够做到这一点，
update the entire network very rapidly and very quickly in like a 32nd time frame or
在短短32秒的时间框架内非常迅速地更新整个网络。
less right for new policies and everything else.
对于新政策和其他事务的权利较少。
I think that's where our substantial challenges are at
我认为那是我们面临的主要挑战所在。
just with the Florida right now.
就在佛罗里达现在。
And looking at, you know, how do we solve that in the in the 5g challenge,
在考虑，你知道的，在5G挑战中，我们如何解决这个问题，
not just from an identity perspective, right?
不仅仅是从身份认同的角度来看，对吧？
Because this really comes back to fundamentally an identity
因为这确实从根本上回到了身份认同的问题。
problem in my mind.
我脑海中的问题。
Right? And that is how do you identify the user?
对吧？那么问题是你如何识别用户？
How do you identify the node?
你如何识别节点？
How do you identify the traffic and so
如何识别交通流量呢？所以~!@#$%^&*()
really saying If we have a trustful source, or a trustful destination,
如果我们有一个可信的来源或一个可信的目的地，
right, it's everything in between that we have to fix to get it there and
对，我们需要解决中间的所有问题才能达到那个目标。
I think Indian is a huge leap forward to get you know, to get as 90% there.
我认为印度式的进步是一个巨大的飞跃，可以让你知道，达到那里的90%。
I think that there's just a little bit more we can do
我认为我们还能做更多一点点的事情。
on the forwarder to really dial in the identity aspects.
在转发器上，我们还需要进一步精确地调整身份识别方面的细节。
And then create the faces dynamically as well.
同时还需要动态地创建面部特征。
Just,take that load off of developers.
只是，减轻开发者的负担。
>> Dan, you have anything you want to add?
>> 丹，你还有什么想补充的吗？
>> I think a lot of it's already been said I'll just add a quick thing in there
>> 我认为已经有很多内容被提及了，我只简炼地补充一点。
that agree with all the comments there.
我同意所有的评论。
I think it's particularly interesting to see how does availability change and
我认为看到可用性如何变化特别有趣，
can I get a highly available network in a session less stateless environment and
我能在一个无状态的无会话环境中获得一个高可用性的网络吗，还有
I think that gives me a lot of
我认为这为我提供了很多
new opportunities I couldn't have explored before.
新的机会，这是我以前无法探索的。
So I, I think, a lot of interesting directions to pursue here.
所以我认为，这里有很多有趣的方向可以追求。
Okay, well, I don't see any other questions.
好的，我没有看到其他问题。
So I guess Dave had around had a follow up about
所以我猜Dave大概有后续的问题。
wondering whether we were requiring that all the NBN routers be physically and
想知道我们是否要求所有的NBN路由器都要进行物理上的安全保护。
logically secured but I don't think that I think that.
我不认为我们只是需要逻辑上的安全保护。
As I heard several of you talk about it, it was more, you know, how do we work
当我听你们中的一些人谈论这个问题时，更多的是，你知道，我们该如何工作
in current environments, and that did not seem to be the requirement.
在当前环境中，那似乎并不是要求。
But so anyway, I was thinking maybe we would just go ahead and wrap up and
但无论如何，我在想也许我们应该继续，然后结束这件事。
I don't know if a lot peace on this we still take a half hour
我不知道是否因为这件事我们还需要再花半个小时。
break or less Somebody want to give us some guidance?
是否有人想给我们一些指导？
>> Yeah, I think we were supposed to come back at 3:15.
是的，我认为我们应该在3点15分回来。
So we'll take it 20 minutes and
那么我们将休息20分钟。
come back at 3:20 >> Great.
回来的时间是3点20分 >> 很好。
>> All right, it was very nice meeting you guys.
>> 好的，很高兴见到你们。
>> All right, see you guys later.
>> 好的，稍后见。
>> Nice meeting you.
>> 很高兴认识你。
>> Thank you very much to all the panelists.
>> 非常感谢所有的小组成员。
>> Thank you. >> Thank you.
>> 谢谢。>> 谢谢。
>> Bye.
>> 再见。